字幕來源：網絡
后期：bongpong
在西部有一個家伙
Way out West there was this fella.
我正要說關于他的故事
Fella I wanna tell you about.
他叫杰弗里·李波斯基
Fella by the name of Jeff Lebowski.
至少那是他親愛的父母給他的
ast that was the handle that his loving parents gave him.
然而他卻不太喜歡
But he never had much use for it himself.
這個李波斯基  稱自己為"酷哥"
This Lebowski, he called himself the Dude.
"酷哥"
Now Dude,
是在我家鄉里  沒人會用的稱呼
that's a name no one would self-apply where I come from.
然而關于這個酷哥的傳奇卻很多
But then there was a lot about the Dude
雖然對我沒多大意義
that didn't make a whole lot of sense to me,
他居住的地方
and a lot about where he lived likewise.
也是光怪陸離
Drifting along with the tumbling tumbleweeds
但這也許是我覺得
But then again,maybe that's why I found the place so darned interesting.
那地方很有趣的原因
I know when night has gone That a new world's born at dawn
人們稱洛杉磯為天使之城
They call Los Angeles the City of Angels.
我倒沒見到什么天使
I didn't find it to be that, exactly.
但那里還是有一些好人的
But I'll allow there are some nice folks there.
因為我沒去過倫敦
Course, I can't say I seen London,
也沒到過法國
and I never been to France,
也沒見過傳說中的內衣女王
and I ain't never seen no queen in her damned undies, as the fella says.
但我告訴你
But I'll tell you what,
在了解洛杉磯之后  并聽了我即將說的故事之后
after seeing Los Angeles and this here story I'm about to unfold,
你會覺得此事的悲慘無奈也是別處少見
well, I guess I've seen something
若我能把這事說下來
every bit as stupefying as you can see in any of those other places,
用英語
and in English, too.
便是死也無憾了
So I can die with a smile on my face
也不會再怨天尤人了
without feeling like the good Lord gypped me.
我將要講述的這個故事...
Now, this here story I'm about to unfold
發生在90年代早期
took place back in the early '90,
大概在我國與伊拉克發生沖突的時候
just about the time of our conflict with Saddam and the lraqis.
我提起這些  是因為一個人...
I only mention it 'cause sometimes there's a man...
我不會說一個英雄
I won't say a hero.
因為英雄是什么呢
'Cause what's a hero?
那時候有一個人...
But sometimes there's a man...
這里說的就是酷哥
And I'm talking about the Dude here.
那個人...
Sometimes there's a man...
在那個時代  那個地方
Well, he's the man for his time and place.
他適得其所的活著
He fits right in there.
就是這個洛城酷哥
And that's the Dude in Los Angeles.
即使他是個懶惰的人...
And even if he is a lazy man,
酷哥很可能是...
and the Dude was most certainly that,
洛杉磯最懶的人
quite possibly the laziest in Los Angeles county,
在世界懶人排行榜的位置也一定很高
which would place him high in the running for laziest worldwide.
那時候有一個男人
But sometimes there's a man...
那時候這個男人...
Sometimes there's a man...
我的思路斷開了
Well, I lost my train of thought here.
不管怎樣
But...
我對他的介紹已經足夠了
Hell, I done introduced him enough.
一次集體的行動
...with them all for a collective action.
這不會停止
This will not stand.
這不會停止  對科威特的侵略
This will not stand, this aggression against Kuwait.
錢在哪里  李波斯基
Where's the money, Lebowski?
我要那些錢  李波斯基
I want that money, Lebowski.
邦妮說你非常富有的
Bunny says you're good for it.
錢在哪里  李波斯基
Where's the money, Lebowski?
錢到底在哪里  混蛋
Where's the fucking money, shithead?
在哪里了...我找一下
It's down there somewhere. Let me take another look.
別耍花招
Don't fuck with us.
你老婆欠了杰奇·特里赫姆的錢
Your wife owes money to Jackie Treehorn,
就是你欠了杰奇·特里赫姆的錢
that means you owe money to Jackie Treehorn.
賴債不還就要吃苦頭  李波斯基
Ever thus to deadbeats, Lebowski.
不  不要...
No, don't do that...
-別在我地毯上  -看見了
-Not on the rug, man. -See?
看到了嗎  李波斯基  看到了嗎
See what happens, Lebowski? You see what happens?
沒人會叫我李波斯基  你們找錯人了
Nobody calls me Lebowski. You got the wrong guy.
我是酷哥
I'm the Dude, man.
你的名字就是李波斯基  李波斯基
Your name's Lebowski, Lebowski.
你老婆叫邦妮
Your wife is Bunny.
我老婆邦妮
My wife? Bunny?
你看到我手指上有結婚戒指嗎
Do you see a wedding ring on my finger?
這地方像是結了婚的人住的嗎
Does this place look like I'm fucking married?
馬桶的坐板放起來了
The toilet seat's up, man!
這他媽是什么
What the fuck is this?
顯然你不打高爾夫
Obviously you're not a golfer.
-吳  -怎么了
-Woo? -Yeah.
那家伙像是個富翁嗎
Isn't this guy supposed to be a millionaire?
操
Fuck.
是啊  你說呢
Yeah. What do you think?
他樣子像個失敗者
He looks like a fucking loser.
起碼我有教養
Hey, at least I'm housebroken.
浪費時間
Fucking time-waster.
謝了  混蛋
Thanks a lot, asshole.
謀殺綠腳趾
我今晚手風很順啊  記分吧  酷哥
I'm throwing rocks tonight. Mark it, Dude.
那是很有價值的地毯  那是...
I'm telling you, this was a valued rug. This was a...
那地毯和我的屋子很搭配
Yeah, man. It really tied the room together.
那是很有價值的...
This was a valued...
-什么東西跟你房間很搭配  酷哥  -我的地毯
-What tied the room together, Dude? -My rug.
你剛才有聽酷哥講故事嗎  唐尼
Were you listening to the Dude's story, Donny?
-什么  -沃爾特
-What? -Walter.
-你剛才有聽酷哥講故事嗎  -我剛在打保齡球啊
-Were you listening to the Dude's story? -I was bowling.
那你就什么都不了解  唐尼
So you have no frame of reference here, Donny.
-你就像一個中途出來打岔的  -沃爾特
-You're like a child who wanders into the middle of a movie -Walter.
什么都好奇的孩子...
and wants to know...
-沃爾特  你想說明什么  -聽我說  酷哥...
-Walter, what's the point, man? -There's no reason, here's my point, Dude.
沒有任何理由...
There's no fucking reason why these two...
是啊  沃爾特  你想說明什么
Yeah, Walter, what's your point?
沃爾特  你想說明什么
Walter, what is the...
聽著  很明顯到底是誰沒搞清楚
Look, we all know who is at fault here.
你到底在說什么鬼話
What the fuck are you talking about? Huh?
不是  你...我...
No, what the fuck are you... I'm not...
我們在說討債打錯人的事情  酷哥
We're talking about unchecked aggression here, Dude.
-他到底在說什么鬼話  -我的地毯
-What the fuck is he talking about? -My rug.
算了  唐尼  歇一邊去
Forget it, Donny! You're out of your element!
沃爾特  那個中國仔  在我地毯上撒尿
Walter, the Chinaman who peed on my rug,
但我找不著他賠償我
I can't go give him a bill!
你到底在說什么
So what the fuck are you talking about?
我到底在說什么
What the fuck are you talking about?
我們討論的不是那個中國仔  酷哥
The Chinaman is not the issue here, Dude!
我在說忍耐的底限  酷哥
I'm talking about drawing a line in the sand, Dude.
如果越過了就要...
Across this line you do not...
還有  酷哥  叫他中國仔不太合適
Also, Dude, "Chinaman" is not the preferred nomenclature.
應該叫亞裔美國人
Asian-American, please.
沃爾特  這些人可不是那些修鐵路的人  那家伙...
Walter, this isn't a guy who built the railroads here. This is a guy...
你在說什么啊
What the fuck are you...
沃爾特  他在我的地毯上撒尿
Walter, he peed on my rug!
他在酷哥的地毯上撒尿
He peed on the Dude's rug.
唐尼  你差不多夠了
Donny, you're out of your element.
酷哥  那中國仔不是重點所在
Dude, the Chinaman is not the issue here.
-那誰是...-杰弗里·李波斯基
-So, who... -Jeff Lebowski.
另一個杰弗里·李波斯基  百萬富翁
The other Jeffrey Lebowski. The millionaire.
那真的很有意思  真他媽的有意思
That's fucking interesting, man. That's fucking interesting.
他有財有勢
Plus, he has the wealth, obviously, and the resources,
所以沒有任何理由...
so that there's no reason, there's no fucking reason
他老婆會出來玩  并欠了債
why his wife should go out and owe money all over town,
然后那些人來你家  在你的地毯上撒尿
and then they come and they pee on your fucking rug!
-我說錯了嗎  -不
-Am I wrong? -No.
-我錯了么  -是沒錯  但是...
-Am I wrong? -Yeah, but...
那么...
Okay then.
那地毯和你家屋子很搭  對吧
That rug really tied the room together, did it not?
-當然了  -那個家伙還在上面撒尿
-Fucking A. -And this guy peed on it.
唐尼  閉了吧
Donny, please.
我能找到那個
You know, this is the fucking guy...
該死的李波斯基
I could find this fucking Lebowski guy.
他叫李波斯基  你不就是這個名字么  酷哥
His name is Lebowski? That's your name, Dude.
他應該賠償我的地毯
This is the guy who should compensate me for the fucking rug.
他老婆出來玩到處欠債  還讓人在我的地毯上撒尿
His wife goes out and owes money all over town, and they pee on my rug?
他們在你的地毯上撒尿
They pee on your fucking rug?
-在我的地毯上撒尿  -那就是了  酷哥
-Peed on my fucking rug. -That's right, Dude.
他們在你的地毯上撒尿
They peed on your fucking rug.
這里就是書房
This is the study.
有各種各樣的獎狀...
As you can see, the various commendations, awards...
-"杰弗里·李波斯基"  -榮譽學位等等
-"Jeffrey Lebowski." -...citations, honorary degrees, et cetera.
-非常厲害  -請隨便查看
-Very impressive. -Oh, please feel free to inspect them.
-不用了  我不是那么...-有請  有請
-Oh. No, I'm not really... -Oh, please. Please.
那是帕薩里那城的鑰匙
That is the key to the city of Pasadena,
兩年前李波斯基先生
which Mr. Lebowski received two years ago
成為那里的杰出市民
in recognition of his various civic...
那是洛杉磯商會的商業成就獎
Oh! That's the Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce Business Achiever Award,
是給...當然并不是每年都頒發的
which is given... Oh, not necessarily given every year.
-這是...-只會頒發給
-Hey, is this... -Given only when
-有價值的人...-是他和南茜(里根夫人)的合照嗎
-there's a worthy somebody... -Is this him with Nancy?
是的  沒錯  那就是李波斯基先生和第一夫人...對
Yes, indeed, that is Mr. Lebowski with the first lady, yes.
-是在里根夫人...-在左邊的就是李波斯基
-It was taken when Mrs. Reagan... -That's Lebowski on the left there?
當然了  李波斯基先生就在左邊  他是個跛子
Yeah. Of course. Mr. Lebowski, on the left... So he's a...
他是殘疾人
You know, a handicapped kind of guy?
李波斯基先生是傷殘人士  對
Mr. Lebowski is disabled, yes.
那是在里根任職總統時拍的照片
This picture was taken when Mrs. Reagan was first lady of the nation.
對  對
Yes, yes.
-并不是加州州長那時候  -拍的好
-Not of California. -Good shot.
約翰教皇他曾經和總統私下會面
In fact, he met privately with the President,
但不幸的是當時沒足夠的時間拍照
though, unfortunately, there wasn't enough time for a photo opportunity.
-南茜是個不錯的女人  -非常棒的女人
-Oh, Nancy's pretty good. -Oh, wonderful woman.
-我們很高興能...-這些是
-We were very happy to... -These are...
這些是李波斯基先生的子女...
Oh, those are Mr. Lebowski's children, so to speak.
同父異母的
Different mothers, huh?
-不  他們不是  -很多種族  十分博愛啊
-No, they're not... -Racially, he's pretty cool?
他們并非他的子女
They're not literally his children.
他們是李波斯基先生的義子女
They're the Little Lebowski Urban Achievers,
他們缺乏接受...
inner city children of promise, but without the necessary means for...
高等教育的條件
Necessary means for a higher education,
于是李波斯基先生資助他們上大學
so Mr. Lebowski is committed to sending all of them to college.
不好意思
Excuse me.
謝謝  謝謝
Thank you. Thank you.
-很好啊  還有多一個位子嗎  -一個...
-Far out. Think he's got room for one more? -One... Oh.
你還沒上過大學
You never went to college.
-不好意思  請別碰那個  -是  是  不  我上過的
-Please, don't touch that. -Oh, yeah, yeah. No, I did,
但是...我大部分時間
but, you know, I spent most of my time
都跑到其他建筑里瞎逛了
occupying various administration buildings,
抽大麻...
smoking a lot of Thai stick,
溜進軍營  還有打保齡
breaking into the ROTC and bowling.
告訴你吧  布蘭特  我就是混過來的
Tell you the truth, Brandt, I don't remember most of it.
好吧  你也叫李波斯基  我也叫李波斯基
Okay, sir. You're a Lebowski, I'm a Lebowski.
非常好
That's terrific.
但我現在很忙  我想你也應該是
But I am very busy, as I imagine you are.
我能幫你什么嗎  先生
What can I do for you, sir?
先生...我有一塊地毯
Well, sir, it's this rug I have.
和我家很搭調的地毯
It really tied the room together.
你在電話上告訴布蘭特  他也告訴了我
You told Brandt on the phone. He told me.
這與我有什么關系
Where do I fit in?
好吧  那兩個男人要找的是你
Well, they were looking for you, these two guys.
-你知道他們...-我再說一次
-You know, they... -I'll say it again.
這些布蘭特已經告訴我了
You told Brandt on the phone. He told me.
我知道發生了什么事情  我知道
I know what happened. Yes, yes.
你知道他們想在我的地毯上撒尿
Oh, so you know that they were trying to piss on your rug.
請問我在那地毯上撒尿了嗎
Did I urinate on your rug?
你是問  是否你親自尿上面了
You mean, did you personally come and pee on my rug?
你好  你會說英語嗎  先生
Hello! Do you speak English, sir?
你會說英語嗎
Parla usted English?
我再問一次  我在那地毯上撒尿了嗎
I'll ask you again. Did I urinate on your rug?
沒有  是那個叫吳的人做的
No. Like I said, Woo peed on my rug.
我只想明白這個  先生
I just want to understand this, sir.
如果誰的地毯被人撒尿了
Every time a rug is micturated upon in this fair city,
我也要賠償嗎
I have to compensate the person?
拜托  伙計  我不是想來這里敲詐的
Come on, man. I'm not trying to scam anybody here.
我只是...
You know, I'm just...
你想找一些施舍  就像其他的人...
You're just looking for a handout like every other...
你有工作嗎  李波斯基先生
Are you employed, Mr. Lebowski?
等一等  讓我解釋一下
Wait. Let me explain something to you.
我不是李波斯基
I am not Mr. Lebowski.
先生  你才是  我是酷哥
You're Mr. Lebowski. I'm the Dude.
別人都這樣叫我  就叫我酷哥吧
So that's what you call me. You know? That or His Dudeness,
或者叫我酷哥斯
or Duder or, you know,
或者酷哥兒  隨便什么樣
El Duderino, if you're not into the whole brevity thing.
你有工作嗎  先生
Are you employed, sir?
工作
Employed?
你不會穿成這樣去工作吧  而且還是在周末
You don't go out looking for a job dressed like that, do you? On a weekday?
這是...
Is this a...
-今天星期幾了  -我有工作的  先生
-What day is this? -Well, I do work, sir.
-如果你不介意  -不  我介意的  酷哥介意
-So, if you don't mind... -No, I do mind. The Dude minds.
這是無法接受的
This will not stand, you know.
這絕對無法接受  伙計
This aggression will not stand, man.
你妻子欠了...
I mean, your wife owes money...
我妻子不是討論的重點所在
My wife is not the issue here!
我希望我妻子  總有一天能學會使用她的零花錢
I hope that someday my wife will learn to live on her allowance,
那是足夠的
which is ample.
如果她覺得不夠  那也是她的問題  不是我的問題
But if she does not, that is her problem, not mine,
就像那地毯  是你的問題一樣
just as the rug is your problem.
每個混混的命運  也是他自己的責任
Just as every bum's lot in life is his own responsibility,
不能去埋怨別人
regardless of who he chooses to blame.
我失去了雙腿  也不會埋怨誰
I didn't blame anyone for the loss of my legs.
我在韓戰的時候失去的
Some Chinaman took them from me in Korea.
但我后來也成功了
But I went out and achieved anyway.
我不能解決你的問題  先生  只有你可以
I cannot solve your problems, sir. Only you can.
-好吧  去他媽的  -去他媽的
-Well, fuck it. -Oh, fuck it.
對  去他媽的  那是你對所有事情的回答
Yes, that's your answer. That's your answer to everything.
紋在前額上吧
Tattoo it on your forehead!
你可別想翻身了  李波斯基先生
Your revolution is over, Mr. Lebowski!
哀悼吧  你這種游手好閑的人
Condolences! The bums lost!
我給你的建議是  像你父母那樣
My advice to you is to do what your parents did!
找份工作吧  先生
Get a job, sir!
游手好閑的總是失敗者
The bums will always lose!
你聽到嗎  姓李的
Do you hear me, Lebowski?
游手好閑的總是失敗者
The bums will always lose.
你的會見怎樣了  李波斯基先生
How was your meeting, Mr. Lebowski?
好
Okay.
老先生說我可以拿走這里任何一塊地毯
The old man told me to take any rug in the house.
非常好
Well, enjoy.
也許我們會再見的  酷哥
And perhaps we'll see you again sometime, Dude.
是啊
Yeah, sure.
如果將來我經過這附近一定來你這借廁所  對了...
If I'm in the neighborhood, you know,
我要上洗手間
and I need to use the john.
吹
Blow on them.
過來吹啊
Go ahead. Blow.
你要我吹你的腳趾
You want me to blow on your toes?
因為我自己吹不到
I can't blow that far.
你肯定他不會介意嗎
Are you sure he won't mind?
他什么也不介意  他是一個虛無主義者
Uli doesn't care about anything. He's a nihilist.
那真累啊
Oh, that must be exhausting.
你沒有吹啊
You're not blowing.
他是我們的客人  李波斯基太太
Our guest has to be getting along, Mrs. Lebowski.
你就是邦妮
You're Bunny.
給我一千塊我就幫你舔
I'll suck your cock for $1,000.
美妙的女人啊
Wonderful woman.
她對性的開放  多么令人激賞呀
We're all very fond of her. Very free-spirited.
布蘭特不能觀看  否則他就要給1百
Brandt can't watch though, or he has to pay $100.
太不可思議了
That's marvelous.
我要去找一個提款機
I'm just gonna go find a cash machine.
今晚我手風很順
I'm slamming them tonight!
你們倒霉了
You guys are dead in the water.
好啊  走著瞧吧  唐尼
All right! Way to go, Donny!
有志者事竟成
"lf you will it, it is no dream."
你遲到20分鐘了  老兄  那是什么鬼東西
Fucking 20 minutes late, man. What the fuck is that?
提奧多爾·何素的著作
Theodore Herzl. Huh?
"猶太人的國家"  酷哥  有志者事竟成
State of lsrael. If you will it, Dude, it is no dream.
你在說什么鬼話
What the fuck are you talking about, man?
我問的是籠子里面有什么
The carrier. What's in the fucking carrier? Huh?
那是辛迪雅的狗  應該是波美拉尼亞狗
Oh! Cynthia's dog. Think it's a Pomeranian.
我不能把它留在家里不然它會吃家具
Can't leave him home alone or he eats the furniture.
辛迪雅和馬迪去夏威夷的時候我要看著它
I'm watching it while Cynthia and Marty Ackerman are in Hawaii.
你帶著那討厭的狗來打保齡
You brought a fucking Pomeranian bowling?
帶來打保齡
brought it bowling?
我不用給它租鞋子  我也不用給它買啤酒
I didn't rent it shoes. I'm not buying it a fucking beer.
他也不能頂替你個衰人  酷哥
He's not taking your fucking turn, Dude.
如果我那該死的前妻在和他男友去玩的時候
Man, if my fucking ex-wife asked me to take care of her fucking dog
叫我幫她看著小狗
while she and her boyfriend went to Honolulu,
我一定會叫她見鬼去吧  為什么不能帶上飛機
I'd tell her to go fuck herself. Why can't she board it?
酷哥  首先你沒有前妻
First of all, Dude, you don't have an ex.
其次  這是一只名犬
Secondly, this is a fucking show dog with fucking papers.
不能帶上飛機  它會發脾氣的  毛也會掉下來
You can't board it. It gets upset. its hair falls out.
-沃爾特...-該死的名犬
-Walter... -Fucking dog has fucking papers.
越線了
Over the line!
不好意思  煙仔  你的腳越線了  那是犯規的
I'm sorry, Smokey. You were over the line. That's a foul.
胡說  記一個8分  酷哥
Bullshit. Mark it eight, Dude.
不好意思  記零分  下一輪
Excuse me. Mark it zero. Next frame.
胡說  沃爾特  記一個8分  酷哥
Bullshit, Walter. Mark it eight, Dude.
煙仔  這里不是越南  現在是打保齡  凡事都講規則
Smokey, this is not Nam. This is bowling. There are rules.
沃爾特  只是...算了吧  煙仔是哥們兒
Hey, Walter, come on. Hey, man, it's Smokey.
他的腳越線了而已
So his toe slipped over a little, you know.
-只是游戲而已  -這是計分賽
-It's just a game, man. -This is a league game.
決定誰進入下一次巡回賽
This determines who enters the next round robin.
-我有錯嗎  -你是沒錯  但我也沒有...
-Am I wrong? -Yeah, but I wasn't...
-我錯了嗎  -沒錯  但我得8分也沒錯
-Am I wrong? -Yeah, but I wasn't over.
給我記分表  酷哥  我要記一個8分
Give me the marker, Dude. I'm marking an eight.
煙仔
Smokey, my friend,
-你在進入一個痛苦的世界  -沃爾特
-you're entering a world of pain. -Walter, man.
記錄一個8分  你在進入一個痛苦的世界
You mark that frame an eight, you're entering a world of pain.
-我不會...-一個痛苦的世界
-I'm not... -A world of pain.
酷哥  這是你的搭檔
Look, Dude, this is your partner.
這個世界變瘋狂了嗎
Has the whole world gone crazy?
這里只有我在乎規則嗎
Am I the only one around here who gives a shit about the rules?
記零分
Mark it zero!
他們在叫警察  伙計  拿開那東西
They're calling the cops, man. Put the piece away.
-記零分  -沃爾特  拿開那東西
-Mark it zero! -Walter, put the piece away.
-沃爾特  -你以為我在開玩笑嗎
-Walter. -You think I'm fucking around here?
記零分
Mark it zero!
好了  一個零分
All right. It's fucking zero.
你高興了嗎  瘋子
You happy, you crazy fuck?
這是計分賽  煙仔
It's a league game, Smokey.
你不能這樣做
You can't do that, man.
這些人和我一樣  是和平主義者
These guys, you know, they're like me, they're pacifists.
煙仔是一個拒絕兵役的人
Smokey was a conscientious objector.
酷哥  你知道我曾經是和平主義者
You know, Dude, I myself dabbled in pacifism at one point.
當然不是在越南的時候
Not in Nam, of course.
你知道剛才這樣他很難受
And you know he's got emotional problems, man.
你是說  超過了和平主義
You mean, beyond pacifism?
他很脆弱  非常脆弱
He's fragile. He's very fragile.
我可不知道
I did not know that.
算了  覆水難收
Well, it's all water under the bridge.
我們一定要進入下一次巡回賽
And we do enter the next round robin.
-我有錯嗎  -不  你沒錯
-Am I wrong? -No, you're not wrong.
-我有錯嗎  -你沒錯  沃爾特
-Am I wrong? -You're not wrong, Walter.
你只是個混蛋
You're just an asshole.
那好吧
Okay then.
我們下周就要對  昆提那和奧布賴恩
Play Quintana and O'Brien next week.
他們應該很容易對付
They should be pushovers.
老兄  你能不能...
Man, would you just...
放輕松  伙計
Just take it easy, man.
那是你對所有問題的回答  酷哥
You know, that's your answer for everything, Dude.
我要指出一點  和平主義不是...
Let me point out something. Pacifism is not...
看看現在伊拉克的情況
Look at our current situation with that camel fucker in Iraq.
和平主義不是用來隱藏的
Pacifism is not something to hide behind.
放輕松  伙計
Just take it easy, man.
我非常冷靜  酷哥
I'm perfectly calm, Dude.
-是啊  揮舞著手槍也算是嗎  -比你冷靜
-Yeah, waving the fucking gun around? -Calmer than you are.
你別那么沖動好嗎
Will you just take it easy?
比你更冷靜
Calmer than you are.
酷哥  這是煙仔
Dude, this is Smokey.
我不想在這件事情上搞僵了
Look, I don't wanna be a hard-on about this,
我知道那不是你的錯
and I know it wasn't your fault,
但我覺得應該告訴你
but I just thought it was fair to tell you
吉爾伯特和我會將這個遞交給賽會
that Gilbert and I will be submitting this to the league
并要求他們取消這一輪的賽事
and asking them to set aside the round.
也許會將罰分記給我們
I don't know, maybe forfeit it to us.
我想只是一個警告
So, like I say, just thought, you know, fair warning.
告訴沃爾特
Tell Walter.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
李波斯基先生  我是布蘭特...
Mr. Lebowski, this is Brandt at...
我在李波斯基先生的辦公室
Well, at Mr. Lebowski's office.
請盡快回電
Please call us as soon as it's convenient.
李波斯基先生  我是
Mr. Lebowski, this is Mel Zelnicker
南部保齡球賽會的比爾
of the Southern Cal Bowling League.
我剛收到一份非正式的報告
I just got an informal report
你的一位隊員  沃爾特·索布查克...
that a member of your team, a Walter Sobchak,
在計分的時候出示槍械
drew a firearm during league play.
如果情況屬實
If this is true, of course,
此行為違反了
it contravenes a number of the league's bylaws
計分的規則...
and also article 27 of the league...
-酷哥  -你好啊  蒙迪
-Dude. -Hey, Marty.
酷哥  我參加了...
Dude, I finally got...
舞蹈比賽
I got the venue I wanted.
我將表演5人舞蹈
I'm performing my dance quintet, you know, my cycle,
周二晚上在杰克森噴泉劇院舉行
at Crane Jackson's Fountain Street Theater on Tuesday night.
希望你能到場給我打氣
And, well, I'd love it if you came and gave me notes.
我會去的  伙計
I'll be there, man.
酷哥...明天已經10號了
Dude, tomorrow's already the tenth.
是啊
Far out.
對了  對了
Oh. Oh, all right. Okay.
把房租塞進我門口就行了
Just slip the rent under my door.
嚴重違規并檢查
serious infraction and examine your standing.
謝謝
Thank you.
李波斯基先生  又是我布蘭特
Mr. Lebowski, Brandt again.
請盡快回復我們  我會派轎車來接你
Please do call us as soon as you get in and I'll send the limo.
希望你不會拒絕  因為那地毯的事情...
I hope you're not avoiding this call because of the rug,
我可以保證  絕對不是問題
which I assure you is not a problem.
我們需要你的幫忙
We need your help, and...
我們非常想見到你  謝謝你  我是布蘭特
Well, we would very much like to see you. Thank you. It's Brandt.
我們有個壞消息
We've had some terrible news.
李波斯基先生將自己隔離在西邊房
Mr. Lebowski's in seclusion in the west wing.
李波斯基先生
Mr. Lebowski.
真有意思
Funny.
回顧我一生的成就
I can look back on a life of achievement,
迎接過無數挑戰
challenges met,
打敗過無數對手
competitors bested,
克服過無數障礙
obstacles overcome.
我比大多數男人有更多的成就
I've accomplished more than most men
而且沒有使用到雙腳
and without the use of my legs.
什么樣的可稱之為男人  李波斯基先生
What makes a man, Mr. Lebowski?
叫我"酷哥"
Dude.
我不知道  先生
Oh, I don't know, sir.
做好準備做正確的事情
Is it being prepared to do the right thing,
無論以何種代價
whatever the cost?
但這樣便可稱為男人嗎
Isn't that what makes a man?
當然  還要有一對睪丸
Sure, that and a pair of testicles.
真會開玩笑
You're joking,
但是  也許你是對的
but perhaps you're right.
介意我抽煙嗎
You mind if I do a Jay?
邦妮...
Bunny.
什么
Excuse me?
邦妮·李波斯基
Bunny Lebowski.
她是我生命中的燭火
She is the light of my life.
你對我流淚感到驚訝嗎  先生
Are you surprised at my tears, sir?
當然了
Oh, fucking A.
堅強的男人也會流淚
Strong men also cry.
今天早上我收到這個傳真
I received this fax this morning.
你可以看到  這是要求贖金的
As you can see, it is a ransom note.
"邦妮在我們手上"
"We have Bunny."
寫自一些不敢公平較量的人之手
Written by men who were unable to achieve on a level field of play.
"籌集一百萬美金"
"Gather $1 million..."
-膽小鬼  -"沒有記錄的  不連續的20元紙幣"
-Cowards! -"...in unmarked, nonconsecutive 20."
-懦夫  -"等待指示"
-Weaklings! -"Await instructions."
-混混  -"這不是開玩笑的"
-Bums! -"No funny stuff."
無賴
Bummer.
無賴  那是個無賴
This is a bummer, man. That's... That's a bummer.
布蘭特會給你講解細節
Brandt will fill you in on the details.
李波斯基先生將給送贖金的人一份大方的報酬
Mr. Lebowski is prepared to make a generous offer to you to act as courier
現在我們只等他們的指示
once we get instructions for the money.
為什么找我
Why me, man?
他相信那些污染你地毯的人...和綁架的歹徒是一伙的
He believes the culprits might be the very people who soiled your rug
而你在此事中的位置很特別
and you are in a unique position to confirm or disconfirm that suspicion.
他認為是那撒尿的家伙干的
He thinks the carpet pissers did this?
酷哥  我們就是不知道
Well, Dude, we just don't know.
"耶穌"
該死的昆提那
Fucking Quintana.
那家伙很棒哦
That creep can roll, man.
-沒錯  但他是個變態  酷哥  -是啊
-Yeah, but he's a pervert, Dude. -Yeah.
不  他是個有性侵犯案底的家伙
No, he's a sex offender with a record.
在齊諾監獄坐了6個月  因為他對一個8歲男孩露下體
He did six months in Chino for exposing himself to an eight-year-old.
他搬去好萊塢之后他還要挨家挨戶地告訴別人
When he moved to Hollywood, he had to go door-to-door
他是個雞奸者
to tell everyone he was a pederast.
-雞奸者是什么  沃爾特  -閉嘴  唐尼
-What's a pederast, Walter? -Shut the fuck up, Donny.
他們給你多少錢
So, how much did he give you?
兩萬  而且我還能得到那地毯
20 grand, man. And, of course, I still get to keep the rug.
-就是那舉手之勞  -是啊
-Just for making a hand-off? -Yeah.
他們還給了酷哥一個傳呼機
They gave Dude a beeper.
-如果那些人傳呼...-如果正在打比賽呢
-So whenever these guys call... -What if it's during a game?
我告訴過他們如果  在比賽當中...
Oh, I told them if it was during league play...
什么比賽當中
What's during league play?
地球不會為你停轉
Life does not stop and start at your convenience,
你這個垃圾
you miserable piece of shit.
-我想...-沃爾特怎么了  酷哥
-I figure... -What's wrong with Walter, Dude?
我覺得這好賺  又沒風險
I figure it's easy money, you know. It's all pretty harmless.
她有可能叫人綁架自己
She probably kidnapped herself.
-什么意思  酷哥  -在地毯上撒尿的人不會做那些事情
-What do you mean, Dude? -Rug-peers did not do this.
看看  一個年輕女子為了錢嫁人
Look at it. A young trophy wife marries this guy for his money.
她覺得他沒給她足夠的錢
She figures he isn't giving her enough, you know.
而她在城里欠了一身債
She owes money all over town.
那個該死的婊子
That fucking bitch!
這是個騙局
It's all a goddamn fake, man.
像列寧說的那樣
It's like Lenin said,
找一個可以獲得好處的人  你知道...
you look for the person who will benefit and, you know...
-"我是海象"(Beatles名曲)  -你會...
-I Am the Walrus? You know, -you'll...
-你知道我想說什么的  -我是海象
-You know what I'm trying to say. -I Am the Walrus.
-那該死的婊子  -是啊
-That fucking bitch! -Oh, yeah!
-"我是海象"  -那...
-I Am the Walrus. -That's...
閉嘴  唐尼
Shut the fuck up, Donny!
弗拉基米爾·伊里奇·列寧
V.l. Lenin, Vladimir llyich Ulyanov!
他在說什么鬼話
What the fuck is he talking about?
他媽的剛才的事讓我發瘋了
Fucking exactly what happened to those...That makes me fucking sick!
-你在乎什么  沃爾特  -那些該死的有錢人
-Well, what do you care, Walter? -Those rich fucks.
這件該死的事情
This whole fucking thing.
當年我沒能夠親眼見到好哥們在泥沼中死去
I did not watch my buddies die face down in the muck
那個該死的賤貨
so that this fucking strumpet,
該死的妓女...
this fucking whore, could waltz around...
我不覺得這與越戰有什么聯系  老兄
I don't see any connection with Vietnam, man.
有文字上的聯系  酷哥
Well, there isn't a literal connection, Dude.
不  沃爾特  沒有任何聯系
No, Walter, face it, there isn't any connection.
-到你了  -那是你的理解
-Your roll. -Have it your way.
-到你了  -但我要說的是
-Your roll. -But my point is...
-我要說的是...-你準備好被宰了嗎
-My point is... -Are you ready to be fucked, man?
我知道你們進了半決賽
I see you rolled your way into the semis.
我的天啊
Dios mfo, man.
里奧和我會將你們干掉的
Liam and me, we're gonna fuck you up.
是嗎  那就像是...你的一廂情愿  伙計
Yeah? Well, you know, that's just like your opinion, man.
我告訴你  蠢貨
Let me tell you something, pendejo.
你若敢對我們掏家伙
You pull any of your crazy shit with us,
你的肉就會飛到球道上
you flash a piece out on the lanes,
我會扣動扳機
I'll take it away from you and stick it up your ass
叫你屁眼開花...打到沒子彈為止
and pull the fucking trigger till it goes click.
"耶穌"
Jesus.
你說了  伙計
You said it, man.
沒人可以斗得過耶穌
Nobody fucks with the Jesus.
記得那個8歲的小男孩吧  酷哥
Eight-year-olds, Dude.
他們80分鐘前呼叫的
They called about? minutes ago.
他們想讓你帶錢去  開車到405公路北面
They want you to take the money, drive north on the 405.
40分鐘后
They will call you on the portable phone
會有人打電話給你指示
with instructions in about 40 minutes.
只能有一個人
One person only.
他們說得很清楚  不然我就和你一起去了
They were very clear on that, or I'd go with you. One person only.
-你的下巴怎么了  -沒什么
-What happened to yourjaw? -Oh, nothing, man.
錢在這里
Here's the money.
還有電話
And the phone.
拜托  酷哥  請你按照他們的指示
Please, Dude, follow whatever instructions they give.
-好的  -她的性命就在你手上
-All right. -Her life is in your hands.
別那樣說
Man, don't say that.
李波斯基先生要我重復的  她的性命就在你手上
Mr. Lebowski asked me to repeat that, her life is in your hands.
媽的
Oh, shit, man.
她的性命就在你手上  酷哥
Her life is in your hands, Dude.
完事后馬上報告
Report back to us as soon as it's done.
-你在搞什么  -你拿著  我開車
-Where the fuck are you going, man? -Take the ringer, I'll drive.
-拿什么  -箱子
-The what? -The ringer.
調包計  酷哥
The ringer, Dude.
-這都是...-他們還沒來電嗎
-What the... -Have they called yet?
這都是什么
What the hell is this?
我的臟內褲  酷哥  剛想拿去洗的
My dirty undies, Dude. The laundry. The whites.
沃爾特  你帶著這些來一定有什么原因
Walter, I'm sure there's a reason you brought your dirty undies, man.
沒錯  酷哥  要那種重量
That's right, Dude. The weight.
那箱子不能空著
The ringer cannot look empty.
沃爾特  你想的是什么
Walter, what the fuck are you thinking, man?
你說得對  酷哥  我應該想想...
You're right, Dude. I got to thinking.
為什么我們只要那小小的兩萬
I got to thinking, why should we settle for a measly fucking 20 grand...
我們  怎么是我們了  你說你只是想跟我去的
We? What the fuck, "we"? You said you just wanted to come along.
酷哥  我說的是...我們手上拿著一百萬的時候
My point, Dude, is why should we settle for 20 grand
為什么還想著那兩萬  我錯了嗎
when we can keep the entire million? Am I wrong?
是的  你錯了  現在不是在玩游戲  伙計
Yes, you're wrong. This isn't a fucking game, man.
但這就是個游戲  你自己說過的
Oh, but it is a game. You said so yourself.
-她綁架了自己  -我說我想是...
-She kidnapped herself. -I said I thought...
-我是酷哥  -誰
-Dude, here. -Who is this?
酷哥  我是送贖金的人  你要我們怎么辦
Dude. The bagman, man. Where do you want us to go?
我們
Us?
該死的
Shit!
是啊  你懂的  我還有司機
Yeah, you know, me and the driver.
我總不能一邊拿著錢開車
I'm not handling the money, driving the car
然后還一邊講電話...
and talking on the phone all by my...
媽的  閉嘴
Shut the fuck up!
-酷哥  你搞砸了嗎  -那是誰
-Dude, are you fucking this up? -Who is that?
那是司機  我告訴過你...
That is the driver. I told you...
-該死的  -怎么了
-Oh, shit! -What the fuck's going on?
-沃爾特  -怎么了
-Walter... -What the fuck is going on?
他掛機了  你搞砸了  你搞砸了
He hung up, man. You fucked it up. You fucked it up!
-她的性命在我們手上  伙計  -別緊張  酷哥
-Her life was in our hands, man. -Easy, Dude.
現在都毀了  我們什么也沒做到  他們一定會殺了她
We're screwed now. We don't get shit. They're gonna kill her.
-我們搞砸了  沃爾特  -什么也沒搞砸  酷哥
-We're fucked, Walter. -Nothing is fucked, Dude.
拜托  你現在非常不酷哥
Come on. You're being very un-Dude.
他們會再來電的  她綁架了...
They'll call back. Look, she kidnapped...
看到了嗎  什么也沒搞砸  酷哥
You see? Nothing's fucked here, Dude.
什么也沒搞砸  他們只是一幫業余的混蛋
Nothing is fucked. They're a bunch of fucking amateurs.
沃爾特  先閉嘴好嗎
Walter, will you just shut the fuck up?
我在做正事的時候別搗亂
Don't say peep while I'm doing business here, man.
好吧  酷哥  照你說的
Okay, Dude. Have it your way.
-他們只是業余的  -操
-But they're amateurs. -Fuck.
酷哥
Dude.
好了  我們繼續  但不能再耍花樣
Okay, we proceed but only if there is no funny stuff.
好的  好的
Yeah, yeah.
不再耍花樣  行嗎
So no funny sturt Okay?
告訴我們該去哪里
Just tell me where the fuck you want us to go.
那里有個標志
That was the sign, man.
我們要做的  就是帶她回來
So, all we gotta do is get her back.
不能抱怨誰
No one's in a position to complain.
-小費我們留著  -是啊  好極了  沃爾特
-We keep the baksheesh. -Yeah, terrific, Walter.
但你還沒告訴我怎樣帶她回來  她在哪里
But you haven't told me how we're gonna get her back. Where is she?
那是很簡單的  酷哥
That's the simple part, Dude.
我們去交換  讓我把那個家伙打昏
We make the hand-off, I grab one of them and beat it out of him. Huh?
是啊  那是一個很好的計劃  沃爾特
That's a great plan, Walter.
你真是天才  如果我的理解是對的
That's fucking ingenious, if I understand it correctly.
這就像瑞士手表那樣精確
It's a Swiss fucking watch.
沒錯  酷哥  簡單即是美
That's right, Dude. The beauty of this is its simplicity.
一旦計劃變得復雜  什么都會出錯
Once a plan gets too complex, everything can go wrong.
如果說我學到了什么...
If there's one thing I learned in Nam...
我是酷哥
Dude.
你們將要到達一座木橋
You are coming to wooden bridge.
過橋的時候...
When you cross the bridge,
不要停車  將箱子從左邊的窗戶扔出去
you throw the bag from the left window of the moving car.
你們正被監視
You're being watched.
-媽的  -他怎么說  在哪里交換
-Fuck. -What'd he say? Where's the hand-off?
現在沒有交換了
There is no fucking hand-off, man.
我們要在那木橋上將錢扔下去
At the wooden bridge we throw the money out of the car.
開著車將錢扔下去
We throw the money out of the moving car.
我們不能那樣做  酷哥  那樣會搞砸我們的計劃
We can't do that, Dude. That fucks up our plan.
給他們電話  解釋一下  沃爾特
Well, call them up and explain it to them, Walter.
你的計劃太簡單了
Your plan is so fucking simple,
我肯定他們會明白的
I'm sure they'll fucking understand it.
那就是它的美
That's the beauty of it.
-木橋是嗎  -我要把錢扔下去  沃爾特
-Wooden bridge, huh? -Throw them the money, Walter.
不能這樣搞砸了
We're not fucking around, man.
好了  酷哥  木橋就到了  快把調包的箱子給我
Okay, Dude, the bridge is coming up. Give me the ringer, chop-chop.
去你的  沃爾特  我愛你
Fuck that. Walter, I love you,
將來你遲早要面對那事實  就是你是個該死的傻瓜
but sooner or later you're gonna have to face the fact you're a goddamn moron.
-好了  酷哥  沒時間爭論了  -喂  老兄
-Okay, Dude. No time to argue. -Hey, man!
-那木橋  -沃爾特  沃爾特
-Here's the bridge. -Hey, Walter! Hey, Walter!
-沃爾特  -出去了
-Hey, Walter! -Here goes the ringer!
-怎么了  -好了  酷哥  你開車
-What the fuck? -Okay, Dude, you're wheel.
-伙計  混蛋  -時速保持15英里  我滾出去
-Hey, man, what the fuck? -At 15 mph, I roll out.
我回頭將他們其中一個收拾掉
I double back, grab one of them and beat it out of him.
-烏茲沖鋒槍  -烏茲沖鋒槍
-The Uzi. -Uzi.
你不會以為我空手滾出去吧
You didn't think I was rolling out of here naked, did you?
-沃爾特  拜托  -15英里  酷哥  來吧
-Walter, please! -Fifteen, Dude! This is it! Let's take that hill!
沃爾特
Walter!
在我們這里
We have it!
在...我們這里
好了  酷哥
Fuck it, Dude.
我們去打保齡吧
Let's go bowling.
酷哥  像我前妻說的  這不是我能控制的
Aitz chaim he, Dude, as the ex used to say.
那是什么鬼意思
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
我們該怎樣和李波斯基說呢
What the fuck are we gonna tell Lebowski?
他...
Oh, him.
問題到底是什么
I don't know. What exactly is the problem?
問題是...你什么意思  你...
The problem is...What do you mean, what's the...
我們根本沒有...
There was no...We didn't...
他們一定會殺了那可憐的女人
They're gonna kill that poor woman, man!
你在說什么
What the fuck are you talking about?
那女人  是那個婊子自己綁架了自己
The poor woman, that poor slut kidnapped herself.
酷哥  你說過的
Come on, Dude. You said so yourself.
老兄  我說可能她綁架了自己
Man, I said I thought she kidnapped herself.
只有你才那么肯定
You're the one who's so fucking certain.
沒錯  酷哥  100%肯定
That's right, Dude. 100% certain.
他們寄信要求下周比賽
They posted the next round for the tournament.
唐尼  給我閉...
Donny, shut the fuck...
-什么時候  -本周六  昆提那和...
-When do we play? -This Saturday. Quintana and...
周六  那他們就要改期了
Saturday? Well, they'll have to reschedule.
沃爾特  我該怎么和李波斯基說
Walter, what am l gonna tell Lebowski?
我要和負責安排賽事的混蛋說  誰負責來著
I told that fuck down at the league office. Who's in charge of scheduling?
-沃爾特  -博克豪特
-Walter! -Burkhalter.
我跟他們說多少次了  我在安息日不打保齡
I told that kraut a fucking thousand times, I don't roll on shabbos!
-沃爾特  -他已經寄信了
-Walter! -They already posted it.
那么  他可以撤回去
Well, they can fucking un-post it!
誰會在乎  他們一定會殺了那可憐的女人
Who gives a shit? They're gonna kill that poor woman, man!
-我該怎么和李波斯基說  -行了  酷哥
-What am I gonna tell Lebowski? -Come on, Dude.
很顯然她已經厭倦了這個游戲  已經想回家了
Eventually she'll get tired of her little game and, you know, wander on back.
你為什么不能在周六打保齡  沃爾特
How come you don't roll on Saturday, Walter?
我要過安息日
I'm shomer shabbos.
-那是什么  沃爾特  -是啊  同時
-What's that, Walter? -Yeah, and in the meantime,
我該怎么和李波斯基說
what do I tell Lebowski?
周六就是安息日  唐尼
Saturday, Donny, is shabbos, the Jewish day of rest.
那就意味者我不工作  不開車
That means I don't work, I don't drive a car,
他媽的不用開車...
I don't fucking ride in a car,
不能數錢  不開烤箱
I don't handle money, I don't turn on the oven
而且肯定不能打保齡
and I sure as shit don't fucking roll!
天啊
Sheesh.
安息日
Shomer shabbos!
-沃爾特  我要怎么...-安息日
-Walter, how am I gonna... -Shomer shabbos!
-媽的  夠了  我要走了  -別這樣嘛  酷哥
-Oh, fuck! That's it. I'm out of here. -Oh, come on, Dude.
酷哥  酷哥
Dude! Dude!
你就告訴他...
You just tell him...
告訴他我們把錢扔下去了  一切就像...你懂的
Tell him we made the drop and everything went, you know...
是啊  怎么了
Oh, yeah. How'd it go?
沒什么  酷哥車上有些寶貝
Went all right. Dude's car got a little dinged up.
沃爾特  我們沒去交換人質
Walter, we didn't make the fucking hand-off, man!
他們沒拿到錢
They didn't get the fucking money!
他們一定會...他們一定會...
And they're gonna... They're gonna...
他們一定會殺了那可憐的女人
They're gonna kill that poor woman.
They're gonna kill that poor woman!
沃爾特  如果你不能開車...
Walter, if you can't ride in a car,
你怎么去參加安息日儀式
then how do you get around on shabbos?
說真的  酷哥  你真的讓我吃驚了
Really, Dude, you surprise me.
他們不會殺人的
They're not gonna kill shit.
他們一無是處
They're not gonna do shit.
他們能對她怎樣  只是一幫烏合之眾
What can they do to her? Bunch of fucking amateurs.
而且你看看
And meanwhile, look at the bottom line.
現在誰拿著那一百萬呢
Who's sitting on a million fucking dollars?
-我說錯了嗎  -沃爾特...
-Am I wrong? -Walter.
現在誰有一百萬放在我們車子后面呢
Who's got a fucking million fucking dollars sitting in the trunk of our car?
-我們的車  沃爾特  -他們呢  只有我的臟內褲
-Our car, Walter? -And what do they got? My dirty undies.
那些白色內褲
My fucking whites!
酷哥
Say, Dude?
你的車呢
Where is your car?
-誰拿了你的內褲  沃爾特  -你的車呢  酷哥
-Who's got your undies, Walter? -Where's your car, Dude?
你不知道嗎  沃爾特
You don't know, Walter?
停在殘疾人專用區的  可能被拖走了
It was parked in a handicap zone. Perhaps they towed it.
你都知道它被偷了
You fucking know it's been stolen.
肯定有這個可能  酷哥
Well, certainly that's a possibility, Dude.
該死的
Oh, fuck it.
-你去哪里  酷哥  -我要回家  唐尼
-Where you going, Dude? -I'm going home, Donny.
-電話在響啊  酷哥  -謝謝提醒  唐尼
-Phone's ringing, Dude. -Thank you, Donny!
是的...
Yeah.
綠色  有些棕色的  銹跡
Green with some brown, rust coloration.
在車里有什么值錢的東西嗎
And was there anything of value in the car?
有的
Oh, yeah.
一臺錄音機  一些磁帶  還有...
A tape deck, some Creedence tapes, and there was a...
我的公文包
My briefcase.
在公文包里面呢
In the briefcase?
文件
Papers.
只是文件
Just papers.
我的文件  生意文件
You know, my papers, business papers.
-你做什么生意  先生  -我現在失業
-And what do you do, sir? -I'm unemployed.
我的地毯也被偷了
My rug was also stolen.
你的地毯在車上嗎
Your rug was in the car?
不  在這里被偷的
No. Here.
可另外立案了
Separate incidents.
酷哥不在家
The Dude is not in.
你們經常找回那些失車嗎
Do you find them much, these stolen cars?
有時吧
Sometimes.
-但別對那錄音機有太大希望  -還有那些磁帶
-Wouldn't hold out much hope for the tape deck though.-Or the Creedence.
那么...我的公文包呢
What about the briefcase?
李波斯基先生  我想見你
Mr. Lebowski, I'd like to see you.
請回電  我會派車接你
Call when you get home and I'll send a car for you.
我叫瑪迪·李波斯基  我就是拿走你地毯的人
My name is Maude Lebowski. I'm the one who took your rug.
看來那案子已經解決了
Well, guess we can close the file on that one.
請稍等  李波斯基先生
I'll be with you in a moment, Mr. Lebowski.
女性的形態讓你覺得不舒服嗎  李波斯基先生
Does the female form make you uncomfortable, Mr. Lebowski?
-這就是那樣的一幅畫嗎  -在某種意義上  是的
-Is that what this is a picture of? -In a sense, yes.
我的藝術被認為與女性的陰道有關
My art has been commended as being strongly vaginal,which bothers some men.
這個詞讓某些男人覺得不自在
The word itself makes some men uncomfortable.
-陰道  -是嗎
-Vagina. -Oh, yeah?
是的  他們不喜歡聽到
Yes, they don't like hearing it and find it difficult to say,
覺得難以啟齒
whereas without batting an eye,
男人相對應的  就是他的陽具  或者叫...小弟弟
a man will refer to his dick, or his rod or his johnson.
小弟弟
"Johnson"?
好了  李波斯基先生  我們說正事吧
All right, Mr. Lebowski, let's get down to cases.
我父親告訴我  他同意了給你那張地毯
My father told me he agreed to let you have the rug,
但那曾經是我已故母親的一份禮物
but as it was a gift from me to my late mother,
所以他無權贈送給別人
it was not his to give.
現在  你的臉上
Now, your face.
關于這次綁架...
As for this kidnapping.
沒錯  我知道此事  你的角色是送贖金的人
Yes, I know all about it, and I know that you acted as courier.
讓我告訴你  這件事簡直讓人惡心
Let me tell you something. The whole thing stinks to high heaven.
沒錯  但讓我解釋一下地毯的事情
Yeah, right, but let me explain something about the rug.
你喜歡性嗎  李波斯基先生
Do you like sex, Mr. Lebowski?
-什么  -性交  愛的身體行為
-Excuse me? -Sex, the physical act of love. Coitus.
-你喜歡嗎  -我剛在說我的地毯
-Do you like it? -I was talking about my rug.
你對性不感興趣
You're not interested in sex?
-你說的是性交  -我也喜歡
-You mean coitus? -I like it, too.
這是關于男性對女權主義者的偏見  認為我們討厭性
It's a male myth about feminists that we hate sex.
這可以成為一種自然的  "性"致很高的產業
It can be a natural, zesty enterprise.
然而有某些人...
However, there are some people,
被稱為色情狂
it is called satyriasis in men, nymphomania in women,
不能自控地參與  而且沒有任何樂趣可言
who engage in it compulsively and without joy.
-不是吧  -是的  李波斯基先生
-Oh, no. -Oh, yes, Mr. Lebowski.
那些不幸的人不能去愛
These unfortunate souls cannot love, in the true sense of the word.
我們都認識的邦妮  就是其中之一
Our mutual acquaintance, Bunny, is one of these.
瑪迪
Listen, Maude,
如果你的繼母是個性愛狂  我很抱歉
I'm sorry if your stepmother is a nympho,
但我覺得這個與我的...
but, you know, I don't see what this has to do with...
-你有卡魯哇酒嗎  -看看這個吧  先生
-You have any Kahlua? -Take a look at this, sir.
我認識這男人
Oh, I know that guy.
他是一個虛無主義者
He's a nihilist.
卡爾·漢古斯啊
"Karl Hungus."
-嗨  -你好
-Hi. -Hello.
總部說你這里的線路有些問題
Mein dispatcher says there is something wrong with dein Kabel.
是的  請進
Yeah. Come on in.
我不知道出了什么問題
I'm not really sure exactly what's really wrong with the cable.
所以他們派我來  我是個專家
That's why they sent me. I am an expert.
電視機在這里
The TV's in here.
你一定能認出她
You recognize her, of course.
這是我的朋友莎莉
That's my friend Sherry.
她只是來洗澡的
She just came over to use the shower.
這故事非常無聊
The story is ludicrous.
我叫卡爾  維修工人
My name is Karl. Ich bin expert.
你一定是來修線路的
You must be here to fix the cable.
之后的事情  你也應該想象到了
Lord, you can imagine where it goes from here.
他修線路
He fixes the cable?
別裝傻  杰弗里
Don't be fatuous, Jeffrey.
這女人從事色情行業  對我來說是無關痛癢的
Little matter to me that this woman chose to pursue a career in pornography,
更不用說他勾搭上了  杰奇·特里赫姆
nor that she has been banging Jackie Treehorn,
以我們這年頭的話來說
to use the parlance of our times.
然而我是李波斯基基金會的兩個托管人之一
However, I am one of the two trustees of the Lebowski Foundation,
另外一個是我父親
the other being my father.
我們的基金會領養了一些年輕人...
The foundation takes youngsters from Watts and...
是啊  那些成就者
Shit, yeah. The achievers.
沒錯  就是他們  我們對他們感到很驕傲
Little Lebowski Urban Achievers, yes, and proud we are of all of them.
我問父親關于
I asked my father about
在基金戶口的一百萬提款的事情
his withdrawal of $1 million from the foundation account,
他就告訴了我這個綁架
and he told me about this abduction,
但我認為這是荒謬無恥的
but I tell you it is preposterous.
那個私通者想騙取我父親的錢財
This compulsive fornicator is taking my father for the proverbial ride.
-是的  但我的...-我正想說到你的地毯
-Yeah, but my... -I'm getting to your rug.
我和父親相處并不融洽
My father and l don't get along.
他不贊同我的生活風格
He doesn't approve of my lifestyle and,
不必說  我也不贊同他的
needless to say, I don't approve of his.
但我不想就他的行為訴諸法律
However, I hardly wish to make my father's embezzlement a police matter.
所以我建議你向那些壞人...
So I'm proposing that you try to recover the money
要回那一筆錢
from the people you delivered it to.
我可以那樣做的
Well, I could do that.
如果你成功做到了
If you successfully do so,
我會將收回數目的10%作為你的賠償
I will compensate you to the tune of 10% of the recovered sum.
-十萬...-萬  沒錯
-A hundred... Thousand. Yes.
十萬美金
Bones or clams or whatever you call them.
-好呀  但是...我的...-沒錯  還有你的地毯
-Yeah, but what about my... -Your rug, yes.
當然  有了那筆錢  你可以買到對我沒有
Well, with that money you can buy any number of rugs
任何情感價值的地毯
that don't have sentimental value for me.
我還要對你下巴的拳傷道歉
And I am sorry about that crack on the jaw.
那沒什么...
Oh, that's fine. That doesn't even...
這是一位醫生的名片  他會為你服務的
Here's the name and number of a doctor who will look at it for you.
你不必付帳
You will receive no bill.
他是個徹頭徹尾的好人
He's a good man and thorough.
你真體貼  不過...
That's thoughtful but...
請你去找他  杰弗里  他是個徹頭徹尾的好人
Please see him, Jeffrey. He's a good man and thorough.
那么...好吧
Oh, well, all right.
他說  我老婆總是給我麻煩
So he says, "My wife's a pain in the ass.
讓我不得安寧
"She's always busting my frigging agates.
我女兒嫁了一個無用的丈夫
"My daughter's married to a loser bastard.
我的屁股還長了皮疹  不能坐下來
"I got a rash so bad on my ass I can't even sit down.
但我不能抱怨什么
"But you know me, I can't complain."
沒錯
Oh, fucking A, man.
我也得過皮疹  是啊
I got a rash, man. Fucking A.
我告訴你吧  托恩
I gotta tell you, Tone, man,
以前的我總是覺得很沮喪
earlier today I was really feeling shitty, man.
無精打采
Really down in the dumps.
失去了不少錢財...
Lost a little money...
你知道嗎  別想那些了  別想了
Hey, you know what? Forget about it, huh? Forget about it.
沒錯  算了吧
Yeah, fuck it, man.
我不應該再擔心那些事情  生活還要繼續啊
You can't be worried about that shit. Life goes on, man.
好吧  到家了  先生
Well, home, sweet home, Mr. L.
看啊
Hey, yo. Come here.
你那位開大眾汽車的朋友是誰
Who's your friend in the Volkswagen?
他跟隨我們到這里的
Yeah. He followed us here.
他什么時候...搞什么
When did he start... Whoa! What the fuck?
進去里面  你這個混蛋
Get in the limo, you son of a bitch! No arguments!
小心點  我還拿著飲料
Hey! Hey! Careful, man! There's a beverage here!
開始說話  快點  你這個該死的混混
Start talking, and talk fast, you lousy bum.
我們在瘋狂地找你  酷哥
We've been frantically trying to reach you, Dude.
我的錢在哪里  死混混
Where is my goddamn money, you bum?
我們...我不...
Well, we... I don't...
他們沒收到  笨蛋
They did not receive the money, you nitwit!
他們沒收到那筆錢
They did not receive the money!
她的性命在你手上
Her life was in your hands!
這是我們所關注的  酷哥
This is our concern, Dude.
不  伙計  現在沒什么搞砸了
No, man. Nothing is fucked here.
-沒什么搞砸了  -是的
-Nothing is fucked? -No, man.
飛機已經撞毀了
The goddamn plane has crashed into the mountain!
伙計  聽我說  你要相信那些人還是相信...
Man, come on. Who are you gonna believe, those guys or...
我們把錢扔下去了
We dropped off the damn money.
我們
We?
我代表我們
I, the royal we.
像那些社論一樣
You know. The editorial...
我按他們的要求把錢扔下去
I dropped off the money exactly as per...
我得到的信息是很確切的  是吧
Look, man, I've got certain information. All right?
有些事情暴露了...
Certain things have come to light and...
你有沒有想過...
You know, has it ever occurred to you
除了到處跑  還有責怪我什么的...
that instead of, you know, running around, blaming me you know,
以及其他新出現的破事
given the nature of all this new shit,
這事情會比想象之中更加...復雜嗎
you know, this could be a lot more complex...
這也許不是預料中那么簡單的  你知道嗎
I mean, it's not just... It might not be just such a simple... You know?
你究竟在說些什么
What in God's holy name are you blathering about?
我在告訴你我要說的
Well, I'll tell you what I'm blathering about.
我收到信息  伙計
I've got information, man.
有新的問題出現了
New shit has come to light.
而且該死的是...
And, shit, man,
她綁架了她自己
she kidnapped herself.
是啊  對  伙計  看看它  你知道嗎
Well, sure, man. Look at it. You know?
一個放蕩女子...我們是這樣說的...
A young trophy wife, in the parlance of our times, you know.
她在城里欠了很多債  還有那個色情電影制片人
She owes money all over town, including to known pornographers.
不過真的很酷  太酷了
And that's cool. That's cool.
我要說的是她需要錢
I'm saying she needs money, man.
還有...他們肯定會說沒拿到的
And, you know, of course they're gonna say they didn't get it
因為她想要更多
because she wants more, man.
她養了那么多白臉...
She's gotta feed the monkey. I mean...
不要說你從來沒想過這些
Hasn't that ever occurred to you, man?
先生
Sir?
沒有  李波斯基先生  我從沒想過
No, Mr. Lebowski, it had not occurred to me.
我們從沒想過  酷哥
That had not occurred to us, Dude.
好吧  你知道...
Well, okay, you know?
新出現的麻煩和你們并沒有利害關系...
You guys aren't privy to all the new shit, so, you know...
但是...那是你們雇用我去做的
But, hey, that's what you... That's what you pay me for.
說到這個
Speaking of which,
你們現在能否...將我的兩萬元兌現呢
do you think that you could give me my $20,000 in cash?
我本來要找我的會計核對一下...
My concern is, and I've gotta check it with my accountant,
但這樣我必須交很多稅  所以...
that this might bump me up into a higher tax...
布蘭特...把信封給他
Brandt, give him the envelope.
如果你們給現金那就最好
Oh, well, if you've already got the check made out, that's cool.
我們早上收到這個
We received this this morning.
你的使命沒有完成
Since you have failed to achieve,
那是如此簡單的任務
even in the modest task which was your charge,
既然你偷了我的錢
since you have stolen my money,
既然你背叛了我的信任...
since you have unrepentantly betrayed my trust,
我別無選擇只能告訴你這個
I have no choice but to tell these bums
混混該做什么
to do whatever is necessary
你要賠償那筆錢  李波斯基
to recover their money from you, Jeffrey Lebowski.
布蘭特做我的證人  我告訴你
And with Brandt as my witness, I will tell you this,
邦妮受到的傷害
any further harm visited upon Bunny
將10倍加于你頭上
will be visited tenfold upon your head.
天啦  先生
By God, sir,
我不能再接受另一只腳趾
I will not abide another toe.
那不是她的腳趾  酷哥
That wasn't her toe, Dude.
-那是誰的  沃爾特  -我他媽怎么知道
-Whose toe was it, Walter? -How the fuck should I know?
我知道的是
I do know
-沒有任何跡象表明...-那指甲油  沃爾特
-that nothing about it indicates... -The nail polish, Walter.
好了  酷哥
Fine, Dude.
那指甲油也可以
As if it's impossible to get some nail polish,
涂在其他人的腳趾上
apply it to someone else's toe...
-其他人的...-鋸齒剪刀
-Someone else... -Pinking shears.
他們怎么可以...
Where the fuck are they gonna get...
你要腳趾嗎  我可以找到
You want a toe? I can get you a toe.
相信我吧  肯定有辦法的  酷哥
Believe me, there are ways, Dude.
-你不會想知道的  相信我  -是  但是  沃爾特
-You don't wanna know about it, believe me. -Yeah, but, Walter...
今天下午3點前  我就能給你一只腳趾  有指甲油的
Hell, I could get you a toe by 3:00 this afternoon with nail polish.
-那些該死的混蛋  -沃爾特...
-These fucking amateurs. -Walter...
他們給我送來了一只腳趾  我們本應該很害怕的
They send us a toe, we're supposed to shit ourselves with fear.
-天吶  -沃爾特...
-Jesus Christ! -Walter...
-問題是...-他們會殺了她的  沃爾特
-The point is... -They're gonna kill her, Walter,
然后他們就要來殺我
and then they're gonna kill me.
酷哥  那...
Dude, that's...
那只是威脅的手段
That's just the stress talking, man.
這讓我覺得...是一些對他人無害的犯罪
Now, so far we have what appears to me to be a series of victimless crimes.
-那腳趾呢  -別說那腳趾了
-What about the toe? -Forget about the fucking toe!
不好意思  你們可以小聲一點嗎
Excuse me, sir. Could you please keep your voices down?
這是一間家庭餐廳
This is a family restaurant.
拜托了  親  告訴你
Oh, please! Dear, for your information,
最高法院已經否決了這種限制
the Supreme Court has roundly rejected prior restraint.
沃爾特  這和第一修正案沒關系
Come on. Walter, this is not a First Amendment thing, man.
如果你不冷靜下來  我只能要求你離開
Sir, if you don't calm down, I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
我當年打越戰出生入死
Lady, I got buddies who died face down in the muck
為了你們這些閑人在這里開家庭餐廳
so that you and I can enjoy this family restaurant!
-好了  我要走了  -酷哥  別走啊
-All right, I'm out of here. -Hey, Dude, don't go away, man.
這事你我都有份  涉及到我們基本的自由
Come on. This affects all of us, man! it's our basic freedoms!
我不走
I'm staying.
我喝完我的咖啡
I'm finishing my coffee.
享受著咖啡
Enjoying my coffee.
酷哥不在
The Dude is not in.
請留言  謝謝
ave a message after the beep. It takes a minute.
李波斯基先生  我是洛杉磯警察局的羅探員
Mr. Lebowski, this is Duty O.e.Rolvaag of the LAPD.
我們找到了你的失車
We've recovered your automobile.
在北好萊塢停車場可以認領
It can be claimed at the North Hollywood Auto Circus there on Victory.
他們的開放時間是...
Their hours there are...
太好了  太他媽好了
Far out, man. Far fucking out!
這是私人住宅啊
Hey! This is a private residence, man.
漂亮的土撥鼠
Oh, nice marmot.
我們要那筆錢  李波斯基  我們要那筆錢  李波斯基
Where is the money, Lebowski? We wants the money, Lebowski!
你以為我們在開玩笑嗎
You think we are kidding or making with the funny stuff?
有些東西你還沒夢想過  李波斯基
We could do things you haven't dreamed of, Lebowski.
-我們什么也不相信  -我們什么也不相信  李波斯基
-Ja, we believes in nothing. -We believes in nothing, Lebowski. Nothing!
明天我們會回來將你的小弟弟切掉
And tomorrow we come back and we cut off yourjohnson.
-什么  -我說我們要將你的小弟弟切掉
-Excuse me? -I said, we cut off yourjohnson!
想想吧  李波斯基
Just think about that, Lebowski.
就是你那雞巴  李波斯基
Your wiggly penis, Lebowski.
也許我們可以  扯下來  李波斯基
Ja. Maybe we stomp on it and squish it.
昨晚被人發現的停靠在橋墩底下
It was discovered last night in Van Nuys lodged against an abutment.
老兄  停在哪
Oh, man. Lodged where?
它沒被撞散了架已經算走運了  李波斯基先生
You're lucky she didn't get chopped, Mr. Lebowski.
他們一定在到處兜風
Oh, man! Must've been a joyride situation.
撞到擋土墻之后就遺棄了
They abandoned the vehicle once they hit the retaining wall.
靠我的公文包啊  老兄  不在里面  該死
Oh, my fucking briefcase, man! It's not here! Shit!
我在報告上看到了  很抱歉
Yeah, I saw that on the report. Sorry.
你得從另一邊進去
You gotta get in on the other side.
后鏡在路上找到的  就在車子旁邊
The side view was found on the road by the car.
那錄音機還在已經算你走運了  還有那唱片
You're lucky they left the tape deck though, and the Creedence.
天啊  什么氣味
Oh, Jesus! What's that smell, man?
也許有個混混在上面睡過
Yeah. It's probably a vagrant slept in the car.
或者被人當作廁所使用
Or maybe just used it as a toilet and moved on.
朋友...
Hey, man,
你一定能找到那幫家伙
are you gonna find these guys?
或者...總有一些線索...
Or, you know, I mean... You got any promising leads or...
線索
Leads?
當然有了
Yeah. Sure.
我會和罪案調查組的人說的
I'll just check with the boys down at the crime lab.
他們有4個人可以調查這案子
They got four more detectives working on the case.
我們只是來換班的
They got us working in shifts!
線索
Leads!
我唯一的愿望就是在那幫德國佬切掉我小弟弟之前
My only hope is that the big Lebowski kills me
讓那老李波斯基殺了我
before the Germans can cut my dick off.
線索
Leads!
那太荒謬了  酷哥
Now, that is just ridiculous, Dude.
沒人會切掉你的小弟弟
No one's going to cut your dick off.
-謝謝你  沃爾特  -我沒說什么
-Thank you, Walter. -Not if I have anything to say about it.
謝謝  沃爾特
Thank you, Walter.
-這讓我覺得非常安全  -酷哥
-That makes me feel very secure. -Dude?
-讓我內心非常溫暖  -酷哥
-That makes me feel very warm inside, man. -Dude?
這件麻煩的事情
This whole fucking thing.
我可以和那帶著尿跡的地毯留在這里
I could be sitting here with just pee stains on my rug.
-但我不會那樣  -沒錯  該死的德國佬
-But no, man, I got a, you know... -Yeah. Fucking Germans.
什么也沒改變
Nothing changes.
-該死的納粹  -他們是納粹嗎  酷哥
-Fucking Nazis. -They were Nazis, Dude?
行了吧  唐尼  他們以閹割作為恐嚇
Oh, come on, Donny. They were threatening castration!
我們要在這里喋喋不休嗎
Are we gonna split hairs here?
-不  -我錯了嗎
-No. -Am I wrong?
-好吧  他沒...-他們是虛無主義者
-Well, he didn't... -Man, they were nihilists, man.
他們一直說自己什么也不相信
They kept saying they believed in nothing.
虛無主義者
Nihilists.
該死的
Fuck me.
說說你對社會主義有什么要求吧  酷哥
I mean, say what you want about the tenets of national socialism, Dude.
-起碼這是一種思潮  -是啊
-At least it's an ethos. -Yeah.
我們不要忘記...不要忘記  酷哥...
And, also, let's not forget... Let's not forget, Dude,
收養野生動物  那兩棲嚙齒動物
that keeping wildlife, an amphibious rodent,
在這城市里面...
for, you know, domestic Within the city...
-也是違反法律的  -你現在成了動物管理員了嗎
-That ain't legal, either. -What are you, a fucking park ranger now?
不  我只是想...
No! I'm just trying to...
誰在乎那該死的土撥鼠呢
Who gives a shit about the fucking marmot?
-我們只是在表示同情  酷哥  -該死的同情
-We are sympathizing here, Dude. -Fuck sympathy.
我不需要你們的同情  我要留著我的小弟弟
I don't need your fucking sympathy, man. I need my fucking johnson.
你要來做什么呢  酷哥  你要振作起來
What do you need that for, Dude? You have got to buck up, man!
你不能帶著負面的影響參加比賽
You cannot drag this negative energy into the tournament.
操那比賽  操你的  沃爾特
Fuck the tournament. Fuck you, Walter.
操那比賽
Fuck the tournament?
好吧  酷哥  我明白你的心情
Okay, Dude. I can see you don't want to be cheered up here.
走吧  唐尼  我們去打一輪吧
Come on, Donny. Let's go get us a lane.
-再來一杯  加里  -好的  酷哥
-Another Caucasian, Gary. -Right, Dude.
-你看這都什么朋友  加里  -是啊  酷哥
-Friends like these, huh, Gary? -That's right, Dude.
-有好的撒爾沙酒嗎  -蘇城的撒爾沙酒
-You got a good sarsaparilla? -Sioux City Sarsaparilla?
是啊  那里的很好
Yeah. That's a good one.
你好嗎  酷哥
How're you doing there, Dude?
不是很好
Not too good, man.
-很不順心是吧  -是啊
-One of those days, huh? -Yeah.
一個比我賢明的人說過
Well, a wiser fellow than myself once said,
有時候你吃掉熊...
"Sometimes you eat the bear and..."
非常感謝
Much obliged.
有時候...熊吃你
"Sometimes the bear, well, he eats you."
那是東方諺語嗎
That some kind of Eastern thing?
很遙遠的
Far from it.
我喜歡你的風格  酷哥
I like your style, Dude.
我也在鉆研你的風格
Oh, well, I dig your style, too, man.
你的風格很牛仔
Got a whole cowboy thing going.
謝謝
Thank you.
還有一件事  酷哥
There's just one thing, Dude.
什么
What's that?
你說話有必要帶那么多臟字嗎
Do you have to use so many cuss words?
你他媽的在說什么
What the fuck are you talking about?
好吧  酷哥  堅持你的方式
Okay, Dude. Have it your way.
放輕松  酷哥
Take her easy, Dude.
當然  謝謝
Yeah. Thanks, man.
你的電話  酷哥
Call for you, Dude.
-喂  -杰弗里  你還沒去看醫生
-Hello? -Jeffrey, you have not gone to the doctor.
是啊  我還沒去
Oh, yeah, no. No, I haven't yet.
我想馬上見你
I'd like to see you immediately.
-你就是李波斯基  -是啊
-So, you're Lebowski. -Yeah.
瑪迪將你的事情都告訴我了
Maude has told me all about you.
她很快就回來  請坐
She'll be back in a minute. Sit down.
-要喝點什么嗎  -好的  白色俄羅斯
-Do you want a drink? -Yeah, sure. White Russian.
酒吧臺在那邊
The bar's over there.
-你做什么的  李波斯基  -你他媽的是什么人
-So, what do you do, Lebowski? -Who the fuck are you, man?
-瑪迪的一個朋友  -是嗎  屁股裂開的朋友
-Just a friend of Maudie's. -Yeah? The friend with the cleft asshole?
-你做什么的  -沒什么
-What do you do? -Oh, nothing much.
-你好  杰弗里  -你好
-Hello, Jeffrey. -Hello.
你好嗎  聽著  瑪迪
Yeah. How are you? Listen, Maude.
我必須...
I got to
向你請辭
tender my resignation or whatever
因為...你母親似乎...真的被綁架了
because looks like your mother really was kidnapped after all.
幾乎可以肯定她不是
She most certainly was not.
你為什么有時候不肯聽些客觀的意見
Hey, man, why don't you fucking listen occasionally?
你也許可以學到什么  現在  我得...
You might learn something. Now, I got...
別稱呼她為我母親
Please don't call her my mother.
她是個罪犯而不是受害者
She's most definitely the perpetrator and not the victim.
我告訴你  我得到了非常確切的證據
I'm telling you, I've got pretty definitive evidence.
-從誰那里得來  -那個男人  奧利
-From who? -From the main guy, Uli.
奧利·庫克爾  她在色情電影里面的搭檔
Uli Kunkel? Her costar in the beaver picture?
那電影...你認識那男人
You mean vagina? I mean, you know the guy?
我已經介紹過他
I might have introduced them, for all I know.
你記得奧利嗎
Do you remember Uli?
他過去是個音樂家
He's a musician. Used to have a group, Autobahn.
看看我的收藏  70年代后期發行過一張唱片
Look in my LP's. They released one album in the late '70s.
類似電子流行音樂
Their music is sort of a techno pop.
-他在假扮誘騙者  -好吧  是啊
-So he's pretending to be the abductor? -Well, yeah.
看吧  杰弗里  你也不會綁架一個熟悉的人
Look, Jeffrey, you don't really kidnap someone you're acquainted with.
綁架就不能
The whole idea is that the hostage can't be able to
讓人質在釋放后指認自己
identify you after you've let them go.
我知道
Well, I know that.
那家伙到底在抽哪根筋  他是誰
What the fuck is with this guy? Who is he?
諾克斯·哈靈頓  錄像藝術師
Knox Harrington, the video artist.
那么錢在奧利那里
So, Uli has the money.
其實不是
Well, no, not exactly.
這個非常復雜  瑪迪
This is a very complicated case, Maude.
很多曲折
You know, a lot of ins, a lot of outs,
諸如此類的事物
a lot of what-have-yous
很多讓我困惑的事情
and a lot of strands to keep in my head, man.
很多酷哥困惑的事情
You know, a lot of strands in the old Duder's head.
喂
Hello?
如果錢不在奧利那里  那么會在誰手上
If Uli doesn't have it, then who does?
是桑德拉
It's Sandra about the Biennale.
我必須接聽這個  你還有那醫生的電話嗎
Look. I have to take this. Do you still have that doctor's number?
-不  真的  其實瘀傷也已經退了  -拜托  杰弗里
-No, really, it's not even bruised anymore. -Oh, please, Jeffrey.
我不想對任何后遺癥負責
I don't want to be responsible for any delayed aftereffects.
[意大利語]
后遺癥
Aftereffects?
[意大利語]
脫下你的短褲好嗎  李波斯基先生
Could you slide your shorts down, Mr. Lebowski, please?
不  不必了  她打在我這里
No, no, man. She hit me right here.
我知道  脫下短褲好嗎
I understand. Could you slide your shorts down, please?
他住在北好萊塢拉德弗德路
He lives in North Hollywood on Radford,
在那間進進出出漢堡包店附近
near the In-N-Out Burger.
不對啊  進進出出漢堡包店在卡姆羅斯
No, the In-N-Out Burger's on Camrose.
-是漢堡包店附近  -那里的漢堡包很好吃啊  沃爾特
-Near the In-N-Out Burger. -Those are good burgers, Walter.
閉嘴  唐尼  那小孩在讀九年級  酷哥
Shut the fuck up, Donny. The kid is in the ninth grade, Dude.
他父親是...你準備好聽了嗎
And his father is... Are you ready for this?
一個叫迪比·塞勒斯的作家
His father is Arthur Digby Sellers.
那他媽是什么人
Who the fuck is that?
-迪比·塞勒斯是誰  -是誰...
-Who the fuck is Arthur Digby Sellers? -Who the...
聽說過一個叫"烙印"的節目嗎  酷哥
Have you ever heard of a little show called Branded, Dude?
我知道...
Yes, yes, I...
只有一個人  可以生存的那個
"All but one man died there at Bitter Creek."
我知道那該死的秀  沃爾特  那又怎樣了
I know the fucking show, Walter. So what?
那個該死的迪比·塞勒斯  寫了156章  酷哥
Fucking Arthur Digby Sellers wrote 156 episodes, Dude.
連續劇啊
The bulk of the series.
-不是個容易對付的家伙  -是啊
-Not exactly a lightweight. -No.
而他的兒子是個笨笨
And yet his son is a fucking dunce.
我們要到他家里
Anyway, we'll go there after the what-have-you.
那孩子應該很容易對付的
We'll brace the kid. Should be a pushover.
我們要到進進出出漢堡包店附近啊
We'll be near the ln-N-Out Burger.
給我閉嘴  唐尼
Shut the fuck up, Donny!
我們要對那孩子逼供  應該很容易對付
We'll go out there, we'll brace the kid. He should be a pushover.
我們要奪回那該死的一百萬
We'll get that fucking million dollars back,
如果他還沒花光的話
if he hasn't spent it already.
整整一百萬啊
A million fucking clams.
-是啊  我們就要到...-進進出出漢堡包店了
-And, yes, we'll be near the... -In-N-Out.
-噓  噓  -吃些漢堡包  喝幾杯啤酒  說幾個笑話
-Shh! Shh! -Some burgers, some beers. A few laughs.
我們的麻煩就要結束了  酷哥
Our fucking troubles are over, Dude.
該死的
Oh, fuck me, man.
那孩子已經把錢花光了
That kid's already spent all the money, man.
就那輛新車  還遠著呢  酷哥
New Vette? Hardly, Dude.
起碼還剩下90多萬  看他買了什么配件
I'd say he still has $060,000, $070,000 left, depending on the options.
在車里等著  唐尼
Wait in the car, Donny.
誰  皮拉爾是嗎
Yes? Pilar?
我是沃爾特  這是我的助手杰弗里
My name is Walter Sobchak. This is my associate, Jeffrey Lebowski.
我們是來找蘭尼的
We came to talk about little Larry.
-可以進來嗎  -可以
-May we come in? -Yes, yes.
謝謝
Thank you.
就是他  酷哥
That's him, Dude.
你好  先生
And a good day to you, sir!
請坐
Sit down, please.
蘭尼  那位先生來了
Larry, sweetie, the man is here!
他...他還在寫作嗎
Is he... Does he still write?
不  沒有  他有健康問題
Oh, no, no. He has health problems.
我想說的是...
Sir, I just want to say
我們...個人來說都是你的...
that we're both, on a personal level,
龐大的粉絲團里的人之一
really enormous fans.
"烙印"  尤其是前面的章節
Branded, especially the early episodes,
對我們很有啟發
was truly a source of inspiration.
親愛的  過來坐  這男人是個警察
Sweetie, sit down. This man is the police.
不  女士
Oh, no, ma'am.
我們不想給人警察的印象
We didn't want to give the impression that we were police, exactly.
我們不希望報警
We're hoping it won't be necessary to call the police.
但這取決于小蘭尼
But that's up to little Larry here.
對嗎  蘭尼
Isn't it, Larry?
這是你的作業嗎  蘭尼
Is this your homework, Larry?
-這是你的作業嗎  蘭尼  -聽著  孩子
-Is this your homework, Larry? -Look, man, it...
酷哥  這是你的作業嗎  蘭尼
Dude. Please? Is this your homework, Larry?
問他關于車子的事情
Just ask him about the car, man.
這是你的嗎  這是你的作業嗎  蘭尼
Is this yours, Larry? Is this your homework, Larry?
外面的車是你的嗎
Is that your car out front?
-這是你的作業嗎  蘭尼  -我們知道這是他的作業
-Is this your homework, Larry? -We know it's his fucking homework!
錢在哪里  你這個臭小子
Where's the fucking money, you little brat?
蘭尼...你聽說過越戰的事情嗎
Look, Larry, have you ever heard of Vietnam?
-看在上帝的份上  沃爾特  -你真讓人頭痛
-For Christ's sake, Walter. -You are entering a world of pain, son.
我們知道這是你的作業  你偷了我們的車
We know that this is your homework. We know that you stole the car.
-還有那些錢  -還有那些錢
-And the fucking money. -And the fucking money!
我們知道這是你的作業
And we know that this is your homework!
我們要切掉你的小弟弟  蘭尼
We're gonna cut your dick off, Larry.
你快要了你爸爸的命了
You're killing your father, Larry.
好了  這是沒意義的
All right. This is pointless.
該用B計劃了
Okay, time for Plan B.
你也許想看看外面  蘭尼
You might want to watch out that front window, Larry.
這就是惹怒陌生人的后果
Son, this is what happens when you fuck a stranger in the ass!
用語言講不通是吧
A little language problem here.
那臭小子惹我發火
Little prick's stonewalling me.
沃爾特
Walter.
你在干什么
What are you doing, man?
What are you doing?
看吧  蘭尼
Here you go, Larry.
看到了嗎
You see what happens?
看到了嗎  蘭尼
You see what happens, Larry?
-看到了嗎  -這下好了
-You see what happens? -Oh, great.
這就是惹怒陌生人的后果
This is what happens when you fuck a stranger in the ass, Larry.
看到嗎  蘭尼
This is what happens, Larry.
看到了嗎  蘭尼
You see what happens, Larry?
這就是惹怒陌生人的后果
You see what happens when you fuck a stranger in the ass?
看到嗎
This is what happens!
看到嗎  蘭尼
You see what happens, Larry?
看見了吧  這就是惹怒陌生人的后果
Do you see what happens, Larry, when you fuck a stranger in the ass?
這就是后果  蘭尼
This is what happens, Larry!
-我的車  我的寶貝  -這就是后果  蘭尼
My car! My baby! This is what happens, Larry!
這就是后果
This is what happens when you fuck a stranger...
你在干什么  住手
What the fuck are you doing, man? Stop it!
我上周才買到這輛車的
Hey, man. I just bought that fucking car last week!
-對不起  -我要殺了你
-Whoa, whoa, whoa! I'm sorry! -I'm gonna fucking kill you!
-我上周才買到這輛車的  -別這樣  老兄
-I just bought the fucking car last week! -Come on, man.
我要砸了你的車
I'll kill your fucking car, man!
別  別  那不是他的車啊
No, no. Hey, hey, that's not his! Hey!
-該死的  -哦不
-God damn it! -Whoa! Oh, no!
-去你的  -別呀
-Fuck you! Man. -No.
你喜歡嗎  去你的
You like that? Fuck you!
-我要砸了你的車  -不  不  不  不
-I'll kill your fucking car! -No. No, no. No.
我要砸了你的車
I'll kill your fucking car!
我接受你的道歉
I accept your apology.
不  我只是...想從現在開始自己處理
No, I just want to handle it by myself from now on.
不  不  不
No. No. No!
那與此事無關
That has nothing to do with it.
是的  車子熬到回家  你在家里打電話給我
Yes, the car made it home. You're calling me at home.
不  沃爾特  看起來不是的...蘭尼不會說出什么
No, Walter, it did not look like Larry was about to crack!
那是你的猜測
Well, that's your perception.
沃爾特  你說得對
You know, Walter, you're right.
有一句話我還沒說
There is an unspoken message here.
就是  "去你的  別管我了"
It's, "Fuck you! Leave me the fuck alone!"
沒錯  我會去練習的
Yeah, I'll be at practice.
戴上你的尿布  李波斯基
Pin your diapers on, Lebowski.
杰奇·特里赫姆想見你
Jackie Treehorn wants to see you.
杰奇·特里赫姆知道你是哪個李波斯基
Jackie Treehorn knows which Lebowski you are, Lebowski.
杰奇·特里赫姆想見那個游手好閑的李波斯基
Jackie Treehorn wants to see the deadbeat Lebowski.
你要應付的不是白癡
You're not dealing with morons here.
你好  酷哥  謝謝你的到來
Hello, Dude. Thanks for coming.
我是杰奇·特里赫姆
I'm Jackie Treehorn.
你這里地方不錯啊
This is quite a pad you got here, man.
像世外桃源
Completely unspoiled.
-喝點什么嗎  酷哥  -白色俄羅斯  謝謝
-What's your drink, Dude? -A White Russian. Thanks.
白色俄羅斯
White Russian.
-你的色情電影生意怎樣了  杰奇  -我也不知道  酷哥
-How's the smut business, Jackie? -I wouldn't know, Dude.
我是做出版的  娛樂  政治主張
I deal in publishing, entertainment, political advocacy.
-一種僵局  -很遺憾  那是對的
-Which one's Logjammin'? -Yes, regrettably, it's true.
成人娛樂被加上了標準
Standards have fallen in adult entertainment.
這是錄像  酷哥
It's video, Dude.
既然我們要和那些業余的家伙競爭
Now that we're competing with those amateurs,
我們可以投資一些有情節的故事加大生產量
we can't afford to invest in little extras like story,
加入感情
production value, feelings.
人們忘記了...大腦是最大的情欲地帶
You know, people forget that the brain is the biggest erogenous zone.
也許在你身上是的
On you maybe.
當然有利也有弊
Of course, you have to take the good with the bad.
可以用新的技術做一些刺激的事情
New technology permits us to do very exciting things
那些交互式的色情軟件
in interactive erotic software.
未來的沖擊波  酷哥  100%電子化
Wave of the future, Dude. 100% electronic.
我還是用手好了
Well, I still jerk off manually.
當然了  我知道你很迫不及待
Of course you do. I can see you're anxious for me to get to the point.
我們開門見山  酷哥
Well, here it is, Dude.
邦妮在哪里
Where's Bunny?
-我還以為你知道呢  -我怎么會知道
-Well, I thought you might know that, man. -Why would l?
她為了那一筆數目不小的債而從我這里逃跑了
She only ran off to get away from that rather sizable debt to me.
不  她沒逃跑  只是...
No, she didn't run off. She's been...
那綁架的故事  我聽說了  省下吧
I heard that kidnapping story, so save it.
我知道你被夾在中間  酷哥
I know you're mixed up in all this, Dude.
我也不在乎你想從他丈夫那里得到什么好處
And I don't care what you're trying to get from the husband.
那是你的事情
That's your business.
我要說的是我要我的東西
All I'm saying is I want mine.
是啊
Yeah, right, man.
有很多方面
I mean, there are a lot of facets to this,
很多部分...
a lot of interested parties.
不好意思
Excuse me.
怎么了
Yeah?
是啊
Oh, yeah?
那是什么
Where is that?
好了  好
All right. Yeah.
不好意思
Excuse me.
-原諒我  -沒問題
-Forgive me. -No problemo, man.
如果我找到你的錢...
So, if I can find your money,
對我有什么好處
what's in it for the Dude?
那當然是可以商量的  再來一杯嗎
Well, of course, there's that to discuss. You want a refill?
-當然好了  -10%的費用
-Yeah, does the pope shit in the woods? -10% finder's fee.
-好嗎  -好的  成交
-That all right? -Okay. Done, Jackie.
好  我欣賞你做生意的方式
I dig the way you do business, man.
你的錢在一個叫蘭尼·塞勒斯的小孩那里
Your money is being held by a kid named Larry Sellers.
他住在北好萊塢拉德弗德路...
He lives in North Hollywood on Radford,
在進進出出漢堡包附近
by the ln-N-Out Burger.
他是個臭小子
Fucking brat.
但我想你的手下...一定能搞定的  他才15歲
But I'm sure your goons can get it off him. I mean, he's 15.
該死的學生
Flunking social studies.
如果你可以...
So, if you could just
寫一張支票  50萬的10%...
write me a check for my 10% of half a million,
5萬...我馬上就告辭
5 grand, I'll go out and mingle.
你的酒調得不賴啊  杰奇
You mix a hell of a Caucasian, Jackie.
一個15歲的小子
Fifteen-year-old kid.
-那是開玩笑嗎  -不  不  不是玩笑
-Is this some sort of a joke? -No. No joke.
不是開玩笑的  就在那小子那里
No funny stuff, Jackie. The kid's got it.
嗨  伙計們
Hi, fellas.
那小子想要一輛車
Kid just wanted a car.
酷哥只想要回他的地毯
All the Dude ever wanted was his rug back.
我并不貪心
Not greedy.
它真的...
It really
跟我屋很搭調
tied the room together.
酷哥接受了黑暗的洗禮
Darkness washed over the Dude.
就像在沒有月亮的晚上  在海上航行
Darker than a black steer's tokus on a moonless prairie night.
進入一個無底洞
There was no bottom.
杰奇·特里赫姆出品
主演:酷哥
瑪迪·李波斯基
保齡情史
這是你唯一的身份證明
Is this your only ID?
我知道我的權力
I know my rights, man.
你什么也不知道  李波斯基
You don't know shit, Lebowski.
我要一個律師
I want a fucking lawyer, man.
我要...比爾·克斯勒
I want Bill Kunstler, man,
或者朗恩·庫奇
or Ron Kuby.
特里赫姆先生告訴我們...
Mr. Treehorn tells us that he had to eject you
他將你從派對里趕出去
from his garden party,
你喝醉了  并失去控制
that you were drunk and abusive.
特里赫姆先生把什么事都看做女人
Mr. Treehorn treats objects like women, man.
特里赫姆先生對這城市的貢獻很大
Mr. Treehorn draws a lot of water in this town.
但你什么貢獻也沒有  李波斯基
You don't draw shit, Lebowski.
這是個寧靜的海灘社區
Now, we got a nice quiet little beach community here,
而我要保證它的寧靜
and I aim to keep it nice and quiet.
我說明白一點
So let me make something plain.
我不喜歡你在這里搞事騷擾這里的市民  李波斯基
I don't like you sucking around bothering our citizens, Lebowski.
我不喜歡你的鳥名字
I don't like your jerk-off name.
不喜歡你的鳥臉
I don't like your jerk-off face.
不喜歡你的鳥行為
I don't like your jerk-off behavior.
我不喜歡你...怪胎
And I don't like you, jerk-off.
聽明白了嗎
Do I make myself clear?
對不起  我剛才沒在聽
I'm sorry. I wasn't listening.
該死的法西斯
Fucking fascist!
遠離馬里布  李波斯基
Stay out of Malibu, Lebowski.
遠離馬里布  混蛋
Stay out of Malibu, deadbeat!
將你該死的的屁股從我的社區帶走
Keep your ugly, fucking, gold-bricking ass out of my beach community.
天啊...換個頻道好嗎
Jesus, man. Could you change the channel?
去你媽的  如果你不喜歡我的音樂
Fuck you, man! If you don't like my fucking music,
就別坐我的車
get your own fucking cab!
我真的...
I had a really rough...
我要將你踢出去
I'll pull off to the side and kick your ass out.
我今晚真的很倒霉啊  我討厭老鷹樂隊
Man, come on. I had a rough night, and I hate the fucking Eagles, man.
滾出去  出去
Out of my fucking cab! Out! Man!
伙計  嗨
Man! Man! Hey!
天啊
Oh, Jesus!
杰弗里
Jeffrey.
-瑪迪  -愛我吧
-Maude? -Love me.
那是我的浴袍啊
That's my robe.
告訴我你的過去吧  杰弗里
Tell me about yourself, Jeffrey.
其實沒太多好說的
Well, not much to tell.
我曾經是休倫湖港口聲明的創作者之一
I was one of the authors of the Port Huron Statement.
休倫湖港口聲明的原本
The original Port Huron Statement.
不是那經過妥協的第二版本
Not the compromised second draft.
然后...
Then I...
你聽說過西雅圖七俠團體嗎
You ever hear of the Seattle Seven?
那就是我
That was me.
還有另外6個人...
And there were six other guys.
后來做了一段時間音樂經理人
And then the music business, briefly.
-是嗎  -是啊
-Oh? -Yeah.
金屬樂隊的經理人
Roadie for Metallica.
"速度之聲"巡演
Speed of Sound tour.
一幫傻瓜
Bunch of assholes.
然后  做些這個  做些那個
And then, you know, little of this, little of that.
我的事業最近停滯了
My career's slowed down a little lately.
你有什么消遣
What do you do for recreation?
通常是打保齡
Well, the usual.
和開車兜風
Bowl, drive around,
偶爾吃點迷幻藥
the occasional acid flashback.
你的屋子怎么了
What happened to your house?
杰奇·特里赫姆將這里翻了一遍
Oh, Jackie Treehorn trashed the place.
他以為我有你父親的錢
He thought I had your father's money.
他在我不在這里的時候干的
He got me out of the way while he looked for it.
-要雞尾酒嗎  -不了  謝謝
-Cocktail? -No, thanks.
那不是我父親的錢  是基金會的
It's not my father's money. It's the foundation's.
為什么他覺得你有呢  誰知道呢
Why did he think you have it? Who does?
那個中學生蘭尼  真是個該死的臭小子
Oh, Larry Sellers, this high school kid. Real fucking brat.
這是一個非常復雜的案子  瑪迪
You know, this is a very complicated case, Maude.
很多曲折
A lot of ins, a lot of outs.
不幸的是  我得堅持一個很嚴格的用藥規則
You know, fortunately, I'm adhering to a pretty strict, drug regimen
不讓自己放縱  你知道的
to keep my mind, you know, limber,
已經他媽的非常接近你父親的錢了
and I'm very fucking close to your father's money.
我一直在說那是基金會的錢
I keep telling you, it's the foundation's money.
我父親沒錢的
Father doesn't have any.
你說什么  他很富有啊
What are you talking about? He's fucking loaded.
不  那些是我母親的遺產
No, no. The wealth is all Mother's.
不  他是管理者...
No, he runs stuff.
我們的確讓他管理其中一間公司
We did let him run one of the companies briefly,
-但他做得很不好  -不  你知道的
-but he didn't do very well at it. -Oh, he's, you know...
他現在幫助管理一個慈善機構
No, he helps administer the charities now,
而我給他相應的養老金
and I give him a reasonable allowance.
他自己沒錢的
He has no money of his own.
我知道他介紹自己的方式
I know how he likes to present himself.
他的缺點就是虛榮  于是  那個婊子...
Father's weakness is vanity, hence the slut.
你認為他...
Do you think he...
怎么了  你在做瑜珈
What is that, yoga?
這樣可以增加懷孕的機會
It increases the chances of conception.
-增加...-是啊
-Increases... Well, yes.
你以為那是為什么  玩游戲嗎
What did you think this was all about? Fun and games?
我要生孩子
I want a child.
好啊  是  好啊
Okay, yeah, okay.
讓我...讓我解釋一下我自己
But let me... Let me explain something about the Dude.
杰弗里  我不需要一個搭檔
Look, Jeffrey, I don't want a partner.
事實上我不想要一個孩子的父親
In fact, I don't want the father to be someone I have to see socially
不管是名義上的還是什么  我要自己養育我的孩子
or who will have any interest in raising the child himself.
所以那個醫生...沒錯
Oh. So, that doctor... Exactly.
你的臉怎么了
Now, what happened to your face?
杰奇·特里赫姆也那樣打你嗎
Did Jackie Treehorn do that as well?
不  是那個該死的馬里布警察  一個反動分子
No, it was the chief of police of Malibu, a real reactionary.
你的父親...
So, your father...
-我明白了  是這樣啊  -什么
-Oh, yeah, I get it. Yeah. Yeah. -What?
我對這案子的想法...已經很清楚了
Oh, man. My thinking about this case has become very uptight.
沒錯
Yeah.
你父親
Your father.
杰弗里  你在說什么
Jeffrey, what are you talking about?
杰弗里
Jeffrey!
沃爾特  如果你在...快他媽拿起電話
Walter, if you're there, pick up the fucking phone, man.
快點  沃爾特
Come on, Walter.
-快接  這是急事  -酷哥  酷哥
-Pick it up, man. This is an emergency. -Dude? Dude?
沃爾特  我在家  我要你馬上開車來接我
Yeah. Listen, Walter. I'm at my place. I need you to come pick me up.
-我不能開車  酷哥  今天是安息日  -什么
-I can't drive, Dude. It's Erev shabbos. -What?
-安息日  -什么
-Erev shabbos. -What?
-安息日  我不能開車  -伙計
-Erev shabbos. I can't drive. -Man!
本來聽電話也不行的  除非是急事
I'm not even supposed to pick up the phone unless it's an emergency.
-這就是急事啊  -我知道
-This is a fucking emergency! -I understand.
所以我聽了電話
That's why I picked up the phone.
沃爾特  你這個混蛋  我們得去帕薩迪納
Walter, you fuck. We gotta go to Pasadena, man.
快來接我  不然我退出那該死的保齡球賽
Come pick me up or I'm off the fucking bowling team.
快出來
Get out of that fucking car, man!
出來
Get out of that fucking car!
Get the fuck out of the car, man.
出來...
Get out of the fucking...
-你到底是誰  -別緊張
-Who the fuck are you, man? -Easy, man!
別緊張
Relax, man.
我無意傷害你
No physical harm intended.
你到底是誰  為什么跟蹤我
Who the fuck are you? Why you following me around?
-說啊  混蛋  -我是希姆斯兄弟的人
-Come on, fuckhead! Relax, man. -I'm a brother shamus.
希姆斯兄弟
Brother Shamus?
像那些愛爾蘭僧人
Like an Irish monk?
你在說什么鬼話
What the fuck are you talking about?
我叫達菲諾  像你一樣是個私家偵探
My name is Da Fino. I'm a private snoop, like you, man.
-什么  -偵探
-What? -A dick, man.
我很欣賞你的工作
And let me tell you something, I dig your work.
兩頭都應付得了
Playing one side against the other, in bed with everybody.
還能和美人消魂  我不是...
Fabulous stuff, man. I'm not...
別靠近我的女性朋友
Fuck it, man. Just stay away from my fucking lady friend.
我不是來找你的特別女朋友麻煩
Hey, I'm not messing with your special lady.
她不是我的特別女朋友  她是個大麻煩
She's not my special lady. She's my fucking lady friend.
-我只是幫助她懷孕  -伙計  我不是...
-I'm just helping her conceive, man! -Hey, man. I'm not...
你為誰工作  李波斯基
Who are you working for? Lebowski?
杰奇·特里赫姆
Jackie Treehorn?
克納森
The Kneutsons.
克納森是什么鬼東西
Who the fuck are the Kneutsons?
克納森家要尋找他們的女兒
The Kneutsons, it's a wandering daughterjob.
邦妮·李波斯基
Bunny Lebowski, man.
她的真名叫弗恩·克納森
Her real name is Fawn Kneutson.
她父母想找她
Her parents want her back, see?
天啊
Jesus fucking Christ.
她一年前離家出走了
Crazy, huh? Ran away about a year ago.
克納森家說找到她時要給她看這些
The Kneutsons told me I should show her this when I found her.
家族的農場  在明尼蘇達州的
It's the family farm. It's outside Moorhead, Minnesota.
他們覺得這個會讓她思鄉
They think it'll make her homesick. Oh, boy.
他們怎么還能保留那農場
How are you gonna keep them down on the farm once they've seen Karl Hungus?
-她被綁架了  達菲諾  -你不是吧
-She's been kidnapped, Da Fino. -Oh, man.
也許不是的
Or I don't know. Maybe not.
但是她肯定不在附近
But she's definitely not around.
也許我們可以交換信息
Hey, maybe you and me could pool our resources,
職業道德啊
trade information.Professional courtesy?
明白我的意思嗎
Compeers. You know what I mean?
明白  明白  你消失吧  達菲諾
Yeah, yeah, I get it. Fuck off, Da Fino.
不要靠近我的...
And stay away from my special...
麻煩的女性朋友
From my fucking lady friend, man!
我要橘子薄餅
The lingonberry pancake.
[德語]
橘子薄餅
Lingonberry pancakes.
Three pigs in blanket.
[德語]
她要橘子薄餅
She has lingonberry pancakes.
[德語]
我們都搞砸了  什么報酬都沒得到
I mean, we totally fucked it up, man. We fucked up his payoff.
那些綁架的人都被惹怒了
We got the kidnappers all pissed off.
李波斯基經常對我大喊
And Lebowski, you know, he yelled at me a lot,
但他什么也沒做
but he didn't do anything, huh?
-有時候...-不  不
-Well, sometimes it's a cathartic... -No, no.
我是說  既然他知道我什么也做不了
I'm saying that if he knows I'm a fuckup,
為什么要我去找她老婆回來
why does he leave me in charge of getting his wife back?
因為他不想她回來
Because he doesn't fucking want her back, man.
他已經對她沒興趣了  那些都是演戲的
He's had enough. He no longer digs her. It's all a show.
好吧  但為什么他要拿出一百萬呢
Okay, but then why doesn't he give a shit about his million bucks?
他知道我們不會把那一百萬交給綁匪
I mean, he knows we never handed off his briefcase,
但他從沒要求拿回來
but he never asked for it back.
那箱子里面根本沒有一百萬
The million bucks was never in the briefcase.
那箱子是空的
The briefcase was fucking empty, man.
那混蛋想他們殺了她
The asshole was hoping that they would kill her.
你扔出去的是一個誘餌
You threw out a ringer for a ringer.
但為什么要那么急呢
Okay, but how does all this add up to an emergency?
我知道你在說什么  酷哥  他留著那筆錢
I'm saying, I see what you're getting at, Dude. He kept the money.
我要說的是...
My point is...
今天是安息日
Here we are, it's shabbos, the Sabbath,
只是關乎人命的事情才能去做
which I'm allowed to break only if it's a matter of life or death.
別吹牛了好嗎  沃爾特  你根本不是猶太人
Will you come off it, Walter? You're not even fucking Jewish, man.
你在說什么
What the fuck are you talking about?
你是個波蘭天主教徒
Man, you're fucking Polish Catholic!
你在說什么
What the fuck are you talking about?
我和辛迪雅結婚后就改宗了  酷哥
I converted when I married Cynthia. Come on, Dude.
-是  是...是哦  -你知道的
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. You know this.
5年前你們就離婚了
And five fucking years ago, you were divorced.
那你覺得應該怎樣  你離婚之后
So what are you saying? When you get divorced,
你就可以改變信仰了
you turn in your library card? You get a new license?
-不做猶太人了么  -這是公路嗎
-You stop being Jewish? -This is the driveway.
我是一個猶太人
Jewish as fucking Tevye. Man.
這都是因為辛迪雅而產生的病態
You know, it's all a part of your sick Cynthia thing.
照顧她留下的小狗...去那些猶太人集會...
Man, taking care of her fucking dog, going to her fucking synagogue.
你還活在你的過去
You're living in the fucking past.
那是有3000年歷史的傳統
Three thousand years of beautiful tradition, from Moses to Sandy Koufax.
你說得對  我還活在過去
You're goddamn right I'm living in the fucking past!
我...天啊
I've... Jesus.
怎么了
What the hell happened?
我們走  媽的
Let's go. Fuck it.
她在哪里
Where was she, man?
去探訪朋友了
Visiting friends of hers in Palm Springs.
她剛離開的  沒告訴我們
She just picked up and left, never bothered to tell us.
我想那該死的虛無主義者知道她在哪里
Well, I guess the fucking nihilists knew where she was.
酷哥  她沒綁架自己
Jesus, Dude. She never even kidnapped herself.
-這位是誰  酷哥  -我是誰  我是個退伍軍人
-Who is this gentleman, Dude? -Who am l? I'm a fucking veteran.
-走吧  -我是個退伍軍人
-Come on! -That's who I am.
他不應該來這里的  酷哥  李先生現在非常生氣
You shouldn't go in there, Dude. He's very angry.
你好
So, man.
她回來了  但不是因為你們
So? She's back, no thanks to you.
錢在哪里  李波斯基
Where's the fucking money, Lebowski?
從那基金會提出來的一百萬
A million bucks from fucking, needy, little Urban Achievers!
你是個人渣
You are scum, man!
-他到底是誰  -我是誰  我是誰
-Who the hell is he? -Who am I? Who am I?
我是一個非常討厭
Walter. I'm the guy that's gonna kick your phony,
你那些詭計的人
gold-bricking ass, that's who I am. Man.
他知道那箱子是空的
We know the briefcase was fucking empty.
我們知道你自己留下了那一百萬
We know you kept the million bucks for yourself.
你們有你的故事  我有我的故事
You have your story, I have mine.
我說我把錢委托給你們了  而你們偷走了
I say I entrusted the money to you and you stole it.
如果我們想的沒錯的話  你那些該死的錢
As if we would ever dream of taking your bullshit money!
你以為邦妮被綁架了
You thought that Bunny had been kidnapped,
而你很高興
and you were fucking glad, man.
可以用作讓錢消失的借口
You could use it as an excuse to make some money disappear.
你需要的只是一個傻子做你的替罪羊
All you needed was a sap to pin it on. You just met me.
你這個人渣
You... You human paraquat.
這里有一個失敗者
You figured, "Oh, here's a loser, you know, a deadbeat.
一個沒人理會的家伙
"Somebody this square community won't give a shit about."
你不是嗎
Well, aren't you?
-我是  不過...-你們都出去
-Well, yeah, but... -Get out, both of you.
看那該死的混蛋  酷哥  還假扮成百萬富翁
Look at that fucking phony, Dude, pretending to be a fucking millionaire.
你們這些混混  給我滾出去
Out of this house now, you bums!
讓我告訴你別的事情
Let me tell you something else.
我見過很多脊椎炎的例子  酷哥  這家伙是假冒的
I've seen a lot of spinals, Dude, and this guy's a fake.
-該死的騙子  -別靠近我
-A fucking gold-bricker. -Stay away from me, mister!
他可以走路的
This guy fucking walks.
沒什么比這個更加肯定了
I've never been more certain of anything in my life.
走開
You stay away from me!
沃爾特  看在上帝的份上  他是個殘廢
Walter, for Christ's sake, man! He's a cripple.
-別靠近我  -快啊  來啊
-I said! Get away from me! -Come on. Come on.
沃爾特  放他下來吧
Walter, put him down, man!
我會的  酷哥  來吧  小心  寶貝
Yeah, I'll put him down, Dude. Walk! Achtung, baby!
過來  幫我把他放回椅子上面去
Come on, man. Help me put him back in his chair.
當然你會看到一些坦克戰的
Sure you'll see some tank battles,
但在沙漠作戰和在叢林作戰非常不一樣
but fighting in desert is very different from fighting in canopy jungle.
越戰是步兵的戰斗  所以這個對我...
I mean, Nam was a foot soldier's war, whereas this thing should...
小菜一碟
You know, should be a piece of cake.
我有一支M16  而不是一輛坦克
I mean, I had an M16, Jacko, not an Abrams fucking tank.
我和查理(越共的蔑稱)面對面
Me and Charlie, eyeball to eyeball. Yeah.
那才是戰役
That's fucking combat.
那穿黑色長袍的家伙  酷哥
The man in the black pajamas, Dude.
是個該死的對手
Worthy fucking adversary.
-誰穿著長袍  沃爾特  -閉嘴  唐尼
-Who's in pajamas, Walter? -Shut the fuck up, Donny.
我們有的只是...
Whereas what we have here,
那些把毛巾纏在頭上的變態
a bunch of fig eaters wearing towels on their head,
為了弄翻那蘇軍的坦克
trying to find reverse on a Soviet tank.
這些對手不值得...
This is not a worthy fucking adversary.
這是說廢話的日子嗎
What's this day-of-rest shit?
什么胡說八道的
What's this bullshit?
我不在乎  對我來說不重要
I don't fucking care! It don't matter to Jesus.
但你們騙不了我
But you not fooling me, man.
你們也許能欺騙那些比賽委員會的笨蛋
You might fool the fucks in the league office
但你騙不了我耶穌
but you don't fool Jesus.
那些都是胡話
It's Bush league psych-out stuff.
真可笑
Laughable, man!
我本來可以在周六收拾你們的
I would've fucked you in the ass Saturday.
現在改成下周三也無所謂
I'll fuck you in the ass next Wednesday instead.
你們周三有約了
You got a date Wednesday, baby!
他是個同性戀白鬼
He's cracking.
大亞洲的概念...
...the whole concept of age.
很多學者對此有爭議
I mean, many learned men have disputed this
但在14世紀...
but in the 14th century, the Rambam...
他們總算成功了
Well, they finally did it.
他們毀了我的車
They killed my fucking car.
我們要錢  李波斯基
We want the money, Lebowski.
不然我們就殺了那女孩
Ja. Otherwise, we kill the girl.
你似乎忘記了我們的交易了  李波斯基
Ja. It seems you have forgotten our little deal, Lebowski.
那女孩不在你們手上  混蛋
You don't have the fucking girl, dipshit.
我們知道的
We know you never did.
他們是納粹嗎  沃爾特
Are these the Nazis, Walter?
不  唐尼  他們只是些虛無主義者
No, Donny. These men are nihilists.
沒什么要害怕的
There's nothing to be afraid of.
我們還是要錢
We don't care.
否則我們要對付你
We still want the money, Lebowski, or we fuck you up.
-去死吧  你們三個去死吧  -冷靜點  沃爾特
-Fuck you. Fuck the three of you. -Cool it, Walter.
不對  沒有人質就沒有贖金
No. Without a hostage, there is no ransom.
贖金就是這樣的  這是規矩
That's what ransom is. Those are the fucking rules.
他女朋友獻出了一只腳趾
His girlfriend gave up her toe.
她以為我們可以拿到一百萬的
She thought we could get $1 million.
-這不公平  -公平
-It's not fair. -Fair?
那該死的家伙是誰  你們這些娘娘腔的
Who's the fucking nihilists around here, you bunch of fucking crybabies?
沃爾特  冷靜點  聽著  伙計們
Cool it, Walter. Hey, look, pal.
根本就沒什么錢
There never was any money.
老李波斯基給了我一個空箱子
The big Lebowski gave me an empty briefcase,
你們去找他算帳吧
so take it up with him, man.
是啊  我還要拿回我的內褲
And I would like my undies back.
他們要傷害我們嗎  沃爾特
Are these guys gonna hurt us, Walter?
不  唐尼  他們都是懦夫
No, Donny. These men are cowards.
好
Okay!
那我們拿走你們身上的錢  這樣就扯平了
So we takes the money you have on you, and we calls it even.
-去你的  -不  算了吧  沃爾特
-Fuck you. -Hey, no. Come on, Walter.
算了  小事化了吧
Come on, we're ending this thing cheap, man.
-不  是我的東西就是我的  -算了吧  沃爾特
-No. What's mine is mine. -No, come on, Walter.
-別耍花樣  -好了  我有
-No funny stuff. -All right. All right.
-別耍花樣  -我有4...差不多5塊
-No funny stuff. -I got 4 bucks, almost 5.
-我有18塊  -我的東西就是我的
-I got $1? -What's mine is mine.
我們要拿走你們的錢
We fuck you up, man! We takes the money!
過來拿啊
Come and get it.
-我們要收拾你們  -做給我看啊  混蛋
-We fuck you up! -Show me what you got, nihilists.
-去你的  -沃爾特  算了  他有鋼鋸啊
-I fuck you! -Walter, come on. He's got a sword.
有9只腳趾的女人的男朋友
Fucking dipshit with a nine-toed woman!
-去你的  去你的  -去你的
-I fuck you! Fuck you! -I fuck you!
-別緊張  -去你的
-Take it easy, man. -I fuck you!
-這里有4塊  -去你的
-Take the $4. -I fuck you!
去你的
I fuck you!
我有一只保齡球
I'm gonna hit you with the fucking ball, man.
-白癡  -反猶的廢物
-Hey, dickhead! -Anti-Semite.
我要殺了你  我要殺了你
I fuck you in the ass! I fuck you in the ass!
去你的  去你的
I fuck you! I fuck you!
有人倒下了  酷哥
We got a man down, Dude!
天啊  他們開槍了
Oh, God. They shot him, man.
-他們沒開  不  酷哥  -他們開槍射了唐尼
-He's not shot. No, Dude. -Are you shot, Donny?
沒有開槍
There weren't any shots fired.
這是心臟病發  找救護兵  酷哥
It's a heart attack. Call the medics, Dude.
我也想去  但我負傷了
I'd go myself, but I'm pumping blood, might pass out.
堅持住  伙計  你行的
Rest easy, good buddy. You're doing fine.
救援就到了
We got help choppering in.
嗨  先生們
Hello, gentlemen.
-你們就是死者的親屬  -是的
-You are the bereaved? -Yeah, man.
我是弗朗西斯·杜納里  很高興見到你們
Francis Donnelly, pleased to meet you.
杰弗里·李波斯基  沃爾特·索布查克
Jeff Lebowski. Walter Sobchak.
應該是酷哥
The Dude actually is...
-什么  -沒什么
-Excuse me? -Oh, nothing.
我知道你們要帶走骨灰
Yes. I understand you're taking away the remains?
是的
Yeah.
已經放進了骨灰罐
We have the urn.
這應該用信用卡結帳吧
I assume this is credit card?
是的
Yeah.
這是什么
What's this?
骨灰罐的錢
Now, that's for the urn.
沒必要了  我們要將骨灰撒開
Don't need it. We're scattering the ashes.
好的  那么
Yes. So we were informed.
但是...我們必須用一個
However, we must, of course, transmit the remains to you
容器轉交給你們
in a receptacle.
要180美金啊
That's $180
這是我們最便宜的容器了
It is our most modestly priced receptacle.
-我們能否...-180美金
-Well, can't we just... -$180?
最貴的可要3000呢
They range up to $3,000.
-我們...-可以租你們的嗎
-We're... -Can't we just rent it from you, you know?
先生  這里是殯儀館  不是租借的地方
Sir, this is a mortuary not a rental house.
我們只是要將骨灰撒開
We're scattering the fucking ashes! Walter, Walter.
別當我們是傻瓜
Just because we're bereaved doesn't make us saps.
先生  請小聲一點
Sir, please lower your voices.
你們有沒有...其他東西給我們放骨灰的嗎
Man, don't you have, you know, something else we can put him in?
你知道
You know?
這是我們最便宜的容器了
That is our most modestly priced receptacle.
該死的
God damn it!
這附近有超市嗎
Is there a Ralph's around here?
唐尼是一個保齡球好手  也是一個好人
Donny was a good bowler and a good man.
他是我們的同伴
He was one of us.
一個熱愛保齡的男人
He was a man who loved the outdoors and bowling.
他喜歡沖浪  熱愛南加州的海灘
And as a surfer he explored the beaches of Southern California
從圣荷拉一直到普里斯莫
from La Jolla to Leo Carrillo and up to Pismo.
他英年早逝
He died as so many young men of his generation, before his time.
真主  以你的智慧  你帶走了他
In your wisdom, Lord, you took him,
正如你帶走了其他年輕人
as you took so many bright, flowering young men
在科沙  在蘭多
at Khe Sanh, at Lan Doc,
還有北越的364高地
at Hill 364.
那些年輕人獻出了生命
These young men gave their lives,
唐尼也如此
and so did Donny.
熱愛保齡球的唐尼
Donny, who loved bowling.
唐尼·卡拉波索斯
And so,Theodore Donald Kerabatsos,
根據我們所想到的  你最后的愿望
in accordance with what we think your dying wishes might well have been,
我們將你的骨灰
we commit your final mortal remains
投入太平洋的懷抱
to the bosom of the Pacific Ocean
這是你最喜愛的海洋
which you loved so well.
永別了  朋友
Good night, sweet prince.
該死的
Shit.
該死  酷哥  對不起
Oh, shit, Dude. I'm sorry.
-該死的大風  -去你的  沃爾特
-Goddamn wind. Fuck, god damn it, Walter!
-你這個混蛋  -酷哥  對不起
-You fucking asshole! -Shit, Dude. I'm sorry.
跟你一起什么事都倒透霉
Everything's a fucking travesty with you, man!
對不起  那是意外
I'm sorry. It was an accident.
-那些越戰的鬼話是什么  -酷哥  對不起
-What was that shit about Vietnam? -Dude, I'm sorry.
為什么所有事情都和越南拉上關系
What the fuck does anything have to do with Vietnam?
-酷哥  對不起  -你在說什么鬼話
-Dude, I'm sorry. -What the fuck are you talking about?
酷哥  對不起
Dude, I'm sorry.
你...
Fucking...
去你的  沃爾特
Fuck, Walter.
酷哥  別說了
Come on, Dude.
去你的
Hey, fuck it, man.
我們去打保齡吧
Let's go bowling.
-2份蘇打水  加里  -好的  祝你們明天好運
-Two oat sodas, Gary. -Right. Good luck tomorrow.
-好的  謝謝  -唐尼的事我很難過
-Yeah, thanks, man. -I was sorry to hear about Donny.
是啊
Oh, yeah. Well, you know,
世事難料  有時候你吃熊  有時候...
sometimes you eat the bear, and sometimes, you know...
你好
Hey, man.
-你好啊  酷哥  -我還想著能否再見到你
-How do you do, Dude? -I wondered if I'd see you again.
我沒錯過半決賽吧
I wouldn't miss the semis.
-當然  -最近怎么了
-Oh, yeah? -How's things been going?
就...還是那樣  有起有伏
Well, you know, strikes and gutters, ups and downs.
-是啊  是這樣的  -對啊
-Sure. I got you. -Yeah.
謝謝  加里
Thanks, Gary.
好了  我得回去了  保重
Well, take care, man. Gotta get back.
-好的  酷哥  放輕松  -好的
-Sure. Take it easy, Dude. -Oh, yeah.
我知道你會的
I know that you will.
當然了  沒有什么酷哥邁不過的坎
Yeah. Well, the Dude abides.
沃爾特
Walter.
沒有什么酷哥邁不過的坎
The Dude abides.
不知道你是否這樣  但我從中得到安慰
I don't know about you, but I take comfort in that.
看到酷哥一切如常
It's good knowing he's out there,
這讓人很高興
the Dude, taking her easy for all us sinners.
希望他能打進決賽
I sure hope he makes the finals.
將對手打個落花流水
Well, that about does her.Wraps her all up.
酷哥和沃爾特的狀況似乎不錯
Things seem to have worked out pretty good for the Dude and Walter.
這也是一個不錯的故事  你說不是嗎
And it was a pretty good story, don't you think?
逗我笑彎了腰
Made me laugh to beat the band.
但也有淚
Parts anyway.
唐尼之死令我不忍
I didn't like seeing Donny go.
但我知道...一個小李波斯基  就要出現了
But then I happen to know that there's a little Lebowski on the way.
可悲的人類就是這樣繁衍下去
I guess that's the way the whole darned human comedy keeps perpetuating itself
一代接一代
down through the generations.
就如西部的大馬車...橫跨大沙漠...
Westward the wagons, across the sands of time until we...
看看我  又開始長篇大論了
Oh, look at me. I'm rambling again.
希望你們喜歡這個故事
Well, I hope you folks enjoyed yourselves.
在保齡球場上再見
Catch you later on down the trail.
再給我一杯撒爾沙酒好嗎
Say, friend, you got any more of that good sarsaparilla?